(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ふう〜
Phew...
いよいよ、この日がきちゃったなぁ...
Finally, this day has come...
こんなにも、拡大して、
Having grown so much,
巨大な組織になった、桐生会。
the Kiryu-kai has become such a huge organization.
別れるのは、惜しいですが...
It's sad to say goodbye, but...
皆さんは、私の心の中で、
Because all of you will,
生きていくんだからな！兄弟たちよ。
live on in my heart! My brothers.
今日は、私の... 卒業ライブということで...
Today is my... graduation live, so...
実は、お世話になりました、
Actually, the friends who helped me,
本ライブの仲間たちが、
those from this live show,
この事務所に遊びに来てくれることになりました。
have come to visit this office.
とってもね、お別れするのは寂しいですけど...
It's very lonely to say goodbye, but...
この、卒業、最後の、最後のこの場で、
In this graduation, at this final, final place,
皆さんと、たくさん笑顔で、お話しして、
I want to talk with everyone with lots of smiles,
お別れを、したいと、思います！
and say our goodbyes!
それでは、先輩方から、
Now, I'd like to hear from the seniors,
皆さんに、お話を、聞いていきたいと、思います。
and have them talk with everyone.
0期生
0th Generation
では！今日この時間からはですね...
Now! Starting with this segment,
先輩たちですとかね、
I've invited the other hololive members
他のホロライブメンバーにお話を伺いたいと思いまして！
to join me for a final chat.
今日、なんと！
And I'm pleased to announce
あのスーパー先輩方に、来ていただきました！
that the OGs of the OGs are here with me today!
タダーン！
Ta-dah!
イェーイ！
Yay!
（歓声）
Whoo-hoo!
もう、先輩中の先輩方ですからね、
I'm practically a rookie next to you guys.
ちょっと緊張しちゃうんですけれども...
It's making me kinda nervous.
今日は少し、あの、私、卒業するという、ことで、
So today, since I'll be graduating,
やだー！
No!
いかないでー！
Don't go!
卒業しないでー！
Please stay!
お、お話を... 伺いたいと... 思いまして、あの...
I wanted to take this opportunity to speak with you all.
あの...
So, well...
まあ、私のね...
Well, mine...
第一印象なんかちょっとそういうところから聞いていきたいななんて思っているんですけれども...
I thought I'd start with your first impressions of me.
先輩方、どうでしょうか？
Well, what were they?
お？
Oh?
我こそはという人挙手なさってください。どうぞ！
Who wants to go first? Raise your hand! Come on!
はい！はいはいはいはい！
Me! Me! Me! Me!
はいはい、さくらみこ、どうぞ。
Very well, Sakura Miko. Go ahead.
はい！
Right!
まずね、みこの会長への第一印象といえば...
Well, one of my earliest memories of the Chairman...
やっぱり朝ココなんですよね。
...has got to be Morning Coco.
あー、確かにね。朝ココね。
Right, of course!
朝ココは本当、え、朝に配信するのっていう驚きとともに...
First, I was so surprised that you'd do a morning stream.
めちゃくちゃ作り込んでたりとか、ぶっ飛んでたりとか...
Plus, the production values were so high and the subject matter so insane...
うん、うん。
Uh-huh.
もあるんだけどやっぱり、その中で、あ、根は真面目なんだなとか、しっかりしてんなっていうところがすごく伝わった...
But most of all, it made me realize how dedicated and responsible you were at heart.
会長の良さが100%伝わったいい番組だったなって思います。
I think it was a great show that showcased everything great about you.
わかるー！
Yeah, totally!
結構なんか初配信からパンチが効いてたと思うんだけど。
You were always pushing boundaries, even from your debut stream.
本当ですか？
You think so?
うん。
Yeah.
誰もやってないことやってるって感じだったと思う。
You were doing things no one had ever done before.
そうそうそうそう。
Yeah, exactly.
私が初配信見てすげえ爆笑したのは...
What really cracked me up during your debut stream...
お尻が大きすぎてビルを潰しちゃったんです、みたいな...
...was the part where you were like, your butt was so big, you crushed a building.
バーン！そうです、そうです。潰したからね。
Smash! Yeah, that's right.
何言ってるんだろうと思って。すごい面白くて、すごい面白い子来たなと思ってて。
It was so out of left field that I totally cracked up. I thought that this new girl's a riot!
で、そらちゃんとかどう思った？初配信見て。
So, what did you think of her debut, Sora-chan?
あ、気になる。
Ooh, I wanna know!
なんか、いろんな意味で大きいなと思ったのが最初の印象で。
Well, my first impression was, she's really big in a lot of ways.
背も大きいし...
Not only is she tall...
大きいです、はい。
I'm big, all right!
まあ大きいし...
Right, she's really big...
で、なおかつドラゴンっていうことで。
And on top of that, she's a dragon!
すごっ、面白い子が来たなと思ったし。
So she really caught my attention.
やっぱり今までと違って新しいなと思ったのは...
But most of all, the one thing we'd never seen before...
ネイティブな英語が達者すぎて。
...was her perfect, native English.
確かに。
That's for sure.
確かにな。そうだな。
That's true.
いやもう、すごいなって思ったイメージがすごい強かった。
All in all, I was just really impressed.
そうですね。
Yeah.
いや、やっぱね、0期生ってあんまり絡む機会ここちなかったと思うんだけど。
So Cocochi, you didn't get as many chances to interact with Gen 0.
あずきちゃんとかとはどうだった？絡みとかは。
Like, did you ever get a chance to talk to AZKi-chan?
あ、でもAZKi先輩ともね、二人でコラボさせていただいたこともありましたし。
Oh, but we did a collab together, right?
そうそうそう。
That's right!
あのね、ココ会長のあの、Shiny Smily Storyあるじゃないですか。
See, I was really moved when I heard...
あれの英訳の歌詞がめちゃくちゃすごい感動して。
...Chairman Coco's English lyrics for "Shiny Smily Story."
その歌詞をAZKiも歌わせてくださいって一回連絡をして。
So I got in touch and said I wanted to sing those lyrics, too.
そらしたらもう快く、歌詞をすぐさま送ってきてくれて。
And without a moment's hesitation, she sent them to me.
そのエピソードとか忘れられないです。
I still remember that fondly.
私こそ、それ、すごく嬉しかったんですよ。
I was also really flattered to hear from you!
英語のやつがすごい好きだから歌いたいなって言ってくださいまして。
I couldn't believe you liked the English version so much that you wanted to sing it.
えっ！？って。
I was like, "What?!"
まさかのAZKi先輩がね、配信で歌ってくださるとは思わず。
I never thought that the AZKi-senpai would sing my lyrics on stream.
皆さん聞きましたか？いや、最高っすよ、あれ。
Have you guys listened to it? It slaps.
私がね、卒業していなくなっても、ぜひあれ英語、英語の歌詞をぜひ歌っていただきたいななんて...
I hope you guys will keep on singing those lyrics even after I'm gone.
歌うよ！
We will. Of course, we'll sing it!
お願いします！
Please do!
皆さんね、本当に、結構雲の上の存在というか、私にとっては...
To me, it always felt like you guys were in a class of your own.
先輩オブ先輩じゃないですか。
I mean, you're the OGs, after all.
だからちょっと、かなり敬うレベル高かったんで...
I was so in awe of you guys...
なかなかね、自分からどんどん行けないというところが正直あったんですけど。
...that it was honestly hard for me to approach you.
それでも、先輩方から関係なく、ガンガン絡みに来てくれたんで。
But you guys were so proactive about approaching me.
本当にそこは、今でもとっても感謝しております。
To this day, I'm truly grateful for that.
いやー、嬉しいよ。
Gosh, I'm so touched.
なんか、みこ、こんなに敬ってもらうこと初めてだからさ。
I've never had someone look up to me like that.
そんな大先輩とか言われたら...
Calling me an OG and all...
どうしたどうした？
You okay, there?
本当に嬉しい...
It makes me so happy...
あれ、泣いてる？泣いてる？
Uh, are you crying? Are those tears?
会長だけだよ、そんなこと言ってくれるの、会長...
You're the only one who sees me that way, Chairman!
あ、すみません。今の話の中には、みこ先輩含まれてないっすね。
Oh, I should clarify. What I said earlier doesn't include you, Miko-senpai.
なんでだよ！
Wait, why?! How come?!
みこ先輩はちょっと、なんというか、容赦なくいじっていい人みたいになってます。すみません。
Miko-senpai, you're just... I have no qualms about teasing you mercilessly, Miko-senpai.
すみません。
My apologies.
なんでだよ！
Why?!
そらそう。そらそうだよね。
No doubt about it. But it's true.
そらそうじゃねえよ！
Have some doubt!
なんか、3D来たときも、だいぶインパクトがあったイメージがある、ロボ子は。
And I really remember your 3D debut leaving a big impression on me.
確かに！
Yeah, definitely!
こう、首ぐぐぐってなったりね。
Your neck was like "bam, bam, bam."
腰ぐぐぐってなったりね。
And your hips were like "bam, bam, bam" as well.
うん。
Yeah.
いやー、動きうますぎ、ぶっ飛んで一番やばいよ、その動きは。
Why're you so good at that? Those moves are just too much!
すげえ、エンターテイナーだわ。
You're such an entertainer!
これが、できなくなるっていうのはね。なので今のうちに皆さん、好きなだけ見といてください。
I won't be able to do this anymore, so please enjoy it now while you still can!
あの、皆さん本当に、
So, I wanted to say thank you to all of you
私とね、積極的に絡んでいただいて。
for approaching me so proactively.
勝手にね、絡みにくいと思ってただけで、
Maybe I just kind of assumed that you were all hard to approach,
全然皆さんすごく絡みやすくて、
but you're all actually really easy to talk to
本当に感謝しております。
and I'm so thankful for that!
こちらこそ！こちらこそ嬉しい！
No, thank you! Thank you!
でもね、会長はさ、みこたちのことそうやって言ってくれるけど、
But like, Coco, you say all that about us,
卒業してもホロライブにとって大きな存在だったし、
but you're still going to be a very important part of Hololive even after graduating.
ホロライブを大きくしてくれた人だって、みこは思っとるから、
I feel like you've helped make Hololive what it is today,
会長もすごい、レジェンダリーな会長だよ！
so you're a super legendary Chairman yourself.
やったー！
Yay!
会長は伝説だよ！
The Chairman is legendary!
伝説！
You're a legend!
すごいと思う、マジで。
Yeah, you really are amazing.
伝説に伝説って言われちゃったんですけど、いいんですか？こんなこと言われて。
The legends are telling me that I'm a legend... Is it really okay to... accept this praise?
そんなこと言われちゃって…照れますね、そんな。
Aw, me? A legend? You're making me blush.
伝説になっていけ！伝説になっていけ！
Accept your legendary status.
皆さん、本当に今日は、私のために来ていただいて、
Thank you, everyone, for joining me today.
本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you so much!
最後っていうのは寂しいですけど、
It was our pleasure. It's sad that this is going to be our last time together,
どうか私のこと、忘れないでください！
but please don't forget about me!
忘れるわけないだろ！
As if we could ever forget you!
今度焼肉行こう！
Let's go out for barbecue sometime!
いつでも行きましょう！
Yeah, let's go whenever you want!
やめてもホロライブの一員ですから。
Even if you leave, you'll still be a member of Hololive forever!
そうだ、そうだ！
Exactly! Yeah, that's right!
本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you so much!
こちらスーパー先輩方でした！ありがとうございました！
Give it up for the OGs of the OGs. Thank you so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
1期生
1st Generation
では、次は一期生の先輩方に、
Okay! Our next guests are the members of 1st Generation!
来ていただきました、一期生の、
The OG generation!
大先輩方、ようこそ私の事務所へ来ていただきました、ありがとうございます！
Welcome to my HQ! Thanks for coming!
イエーイ！お邪魔します！
Yay! Thanks for having us!
面接会場？ここ。
What is this, an interview room?
面接会場ですね。
It sure is!
どうして桐生会に入りたいんですかね？
So, why did you decide to apply to the Kiryu Group?
俺、強くなりたくて！ボス！
'Cause I'm tired of being a weakling, Boss!
逆じゃないですか、私のほうが圧迫面接されてるのでは、これ。
Actually, we've got it backwards. I'm the one undergoing a stress interview, here.
確かに！
That's true!
あ、じゃあ我々面接官とかってこと？
So that makes us the interviewers?
面接官！
We're interviewers!
今日は私の卒業ライブということで、
So, today's my graduation concert
最後にお話しできる機会ですので、
and my last chance to talk to you guys, at least publicly.
私の第一印象であったりとか、
So I was hoping to ask about your first impressions of me
思い出とか、語る時間を取ろうかと思いまして、
and memories with me and stuff.
いいですか？先輩方。
Would that be okay with you guys?
もちろん！もちろん！
Yeah, of course!
ではここちの第一印象！
Okay, first impressions of Cocochi!
第一印象？
First impressions?
やべえファンキーなのが来た！
"Loose cannon," I guess.
やべえファンキーなのが来たと思ったんじゃないの？
Oh boy, we got a real feisty one.
やべえ？
Loose cannon?
第一印象だけなら、見た目でまず「でけー」ってなったよね。
Well, my first thought when I saw you was, "Huge!"
でけーよね！
She really is huge.
背高いなーって。
Like wow, she's so tall.
何もかもデカかったよね。
Everything about you was huge.
何もかもデカいのが来たなっていう。
Yeah, everything about you.
本当に大物が来たなって感じだね。
I knew you'd do big things, too.
でもさ、デビュー配信の時さ、
But remember her debut stream?
可愛い絵のタッチのドラゴンがホロライブ事務所に落ちてきて。
With the dragon, in that cute art style, crashing into the hololive office.
あ、そうだね！
Oh yeah!
そうそうそう。
That's right!
動画可愛かった。
The video was cute.
清楚なのかなーと思って。
So I was expecting someone girly.
見たら、蓋開けたらFワード飛び交うようなね、強烈すぎてすごかったよね。
But what I found was an F-bomb-dropping, gunslinging dragon.
絶対ここちゃんから学んだ、そういう単語いっぱいある！
I definitely learned a lot of that sort of vocabulary from you!
いっぱいあるよ！
Tons!
メルも！
Me too!
ね！
Right?
マザー…とかね。
Like "mother..." you know.
学んでしまったよ、本当に。
It was quite the education.
あったなー。
Basically,
皆さん第一印象は、割と清楚なドラゴンかな？
your first impression of me was a pure dragon?
お前、話聞いてたか？
Uh, were you even listening?
何言ってんだお前、さっきから！
What are you talking about?
まつり先輩には言われたくないんですけど！
I don't want to hear that from you, Matsuri-senpai!
私は清楚ですよ！
Well I am pure.
ここちはまつりラインを初めて越えた女やから！
You were the first one to cross the "Matsuri Line."
確かに！
That's true.
まつり先輩にそんなふうに認められたら、さすがに、ね。
That's an honor coming from you, Matsuri-senpai!
本当だよ。
It's the truth.
すいませんでございました。すいません、大変失礼いたしました。
Terribly sorry about earlier.
第一印象から、一年七ヶ月くらい経ちまして、
So it's been about a year and seven months since those first impressions.
初めまして...
Nice to meet you...
...どうですか？私の今、あの、今の印象はだいぶ変わりましたかね？
...How is it? Has your impression of me changed much since then?
あ、でもあれじゃない？なんかその、破天荒だけど...
Well, isn't it like... you're reckless, but...
すごい誰よりも真面目なイメージはある。
I have the impression that you're more serious than anyone.
そうだね、頼れる姉御って感じがする。
Yeah, you feel like a reliable big sister.
うんうん！
Yeah!
姉御？いや、私、あの、子供ドラゴンなんで...
Big sister? No, I'm... a child dragon, so...
子供はそんなこと言わないでしょ！
Kids don't say things like that!
ホントだよ！
Exactly!
子供！？子供だと！？
A kid!? You say I'm a kid!?
いや、まあドラゴン界の子供かもしれんけど...
Well, maybe in the dragon world, but...
腰振ってるし！
She's shaking her hips!
そうだよ！
Right!
ホロライブでは姉御だよ！姉御！
In Hololive, you're a big sister! A big sister!
姉御ぉ！？
Big sister!?
ま、まあ、でも皆さん、私にとっては皆さんは頼れる姉御であり、先輩なんで...
Well, but for me, you all are reliable big sisters and seniors...
たくさん、あの、活動してる間たくさん頼らせていただいた。本当にありがとうございました！
I've relied on you so much during my activities. Thank you so much!
こちらこそありがとう！
The pleasure was ours!
いろんなものをね、くれたからね。
You've given us so much.
私の放送画面の最後に... 最後まで放送画面にうんち乗っけてたからな！
Until the very end, she was putting poop on my stream overlay!
いや、まあ、約束なんでね...
Well, that was the agreement...
うわぁ！クソだけにクソって？
Ah, crap! Literally crap, right?
クソだけに約束って？クソだけに...
That's what was on your stream. Crap indeed!
おおー、あれみんなにもあげるよ、うんち。
I'll gladly share the poop with you guys.
思い出として、祭りのアホ毛の代わりに付けとこうかな。
Maybe I'll wear it on my head, as a memento.
くっさ！くっさ！
Ew, stinky-head!
メルの髪飾りの代わりに付けようかな。
Maybe I'll replace my hairpin with it.
やめて！汚いですよ！アイドルじゃなくなっちゃう！
Stop! This is getting filthy! The OGs are gonna lose their idol cred!
皆さん、あの、私との思い出もね、たくさん作りましたけど、なんかすごく印象に残ってることとかありますか？
Well, you've all made lots of memories with me. Is there anything that sticks out in your mind?
ありますか？
Is there?
めちゃくちゃあるね. でも、最初の絡みはARKだったかな、メル。
Well, I first interacted with you via ARK.
あー、そうね、ARKだね。
Yeah, ARK!
私が困ってたら助けに来てくれて、すごい優しい子だなって思った。
When I was in trouble, you came to rescue me. You were so kind.
たくさん一緒にARKで遊びましたね。
We sure had lots of fun in ARK together.
うん。
Yeah.
ARKといえば、ココちゃんに大量のうん... またうんちか！
Speaking of ARK, Coco-chan gave me a ton of poo...
思い出うんちじゃないんかーい！
Are all these memories about poo?!
うんこの思い出しかないじゃないですか！私、1年半以上頑張って活動してきて、最後の思い出うんこって、そんなことないですよ！
Why is it all about poop?! After all I've done in this year and a half, your final memories are of poop?! That can't be right!
でも、めっちゃくちゃね、面白いゲームを教えてもらって、みんなでね、できてるのがすごい楽しいから、これからもね、やっていきたいなって思ってるよ。
But you introduced us to an awesome game that's so much fun to play together, so I plan to keep playing.
めちゃハマってるもんね、アキロゼね。
You got really addicted, AkiRose.
まだまだやりたいことあるからね。
I still have a lot left to do in that game.
みんなでたくさん一緒に遊んで. はあちゃまもね、結構二人でコラボとかたくさんさせてもらいましたけど...
We got to play a lot together, and I teamed up a lot with Haachama, in particular.
これからね、ホロライブ卒業して、OGという形にならせていただくのですけれど、まあ視聴者の皆さんの見えないところになっちゃいますけど、お友達として仲良くしていただけますか？
After I graduate hololive and become an alumna, it'll have to be out of the viewers' sight, but will you still be friends with me?
もう絶対！焼肉行こな！
You betcha! Let's get barbecue together!
行こう！行こう！美味しいもの食べよう！
Yeah, let's!
先輩、あの、皆さん焼肉奢ってください。お願いします！
As kind, senior members, you'll be paying, right?
何でや！世界1位だろうが！
Says the top Super Chatted in the world!
お前が奢れよ！
Yeah! You pay!
いや、私、卒業したら無職になっちゃうんで。無職なんで。お願いします！
W-Well, I'll be unemployed after I graduate... Please, I'm unemployed!
奢るよ！奢るよ！
Well, I guess we'll have to, then.
最後まで楽しくしてくれてありがとうございました！こちら、今日のために駆けつけてくれた1期生の先輩方でした！ありがとうございました！
Thanks for the fun times, including today! That was 1st Generation, who were kind enough to join me today! Thank you so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
2期生
2nd Generation
では！えー、次は2期生の先輩方がこちらの事務所に来てくれました！先輩！
Okay! Our next guests are the members of 2nd Generation, right here in my HQ!
イエーイ！
Hello!
ようこそ、私の卒業ライブへ！
Welcome to my graduation concert.
今日で私、ホロライブをね、卒業、OGという形にならせていただくのですけれど...
Today, I'm graduating from hololive and becoming a former member, an alumna.
先輩方、1年と7ヶ月くらい、お世話になりました！
Thank you for everything this past year and, uh, seven-or-so months!
お疲れ様！ココちゃんありがとう！
Thank you too! Coco-chan! Thank you too! Thank you for everything. Chairman!
ということで今日はですね、あのちょっと第一印象ですとか、
So I was hoping to ask about your first impressions of me,
まあいろいろこの、まあ短い期間ですけどあったこととか、
any memories you made with me during this short period of time and stuff.
少しお話できればと思っていまして。先輩方、何かあの...
Would you like to talk about anything?
思い出とか私の第一印象と今の違いとかありますか？
Or, like, has your impression of me changed since we first met?
やぁね、会長はね、やっぱりさぁ、会長といえばARKみたいなとこあるじゃん。
Well, we can't talk about you without bringing up ARK, can we?
ね、マジでブームだったよね完全に。
It was really booming back then.
めっちゃ流行ってた！みんなやってた！みんなやってた！
It was really popular! Everyone was playing it. It was all the rage.
ね、会長との思い出っていうと、配信では載ってなかったんだけど、
As for memories made with you, it wasn't on stream,
あのボス戦の準備、そんときにね、
but when preparing for some boss raid,
会長がすごい色んなことを語ってくれて、
we talked a lot, even though you just debuted.
「デビューしたけどどう？」みたいな感じで聞いてたら、
When I asked her how things were going, she was like,
「もっとVTuberっていう文化、ホロライブをもっとみんなに知ってほしい、
“I want people to learn about hololive and VTuber culture!
もっと世界中の人に知ってほしいんだ！」みたいなこと言ってて。
I want people all around the world to get to know them!”
なんかその時からそういう大きな夢を持ってるってことすごいし、
It was amazing that she had such a big dream so soon after debuting.
実際ね、やっぱり会長は、もう言い切れないほどのものを残してる人だなって。
And indeed, she's left an indescribable mark on this whole sphere.
いや、すごいなって思う、うん。
She's really amazing, no doubt.
作業しながらやってたんすけど、途中で作業せずに、
I was just goofing off, playing on the floor while working on something.
ARKの海からずっと地面に泳ぎながらずっとやってた...
めちゃ楽しそうじゃん！
Sounds like fun!
ね、懐かしいですね。いろんな思い出がありますよ。どうですか、他の方は？
Yeah, it was! I have tons of memories from those times. Anything else, anyone?
じゃあ初配信を見た時は、なんか本当に日本語めっちゃ頑張ってて、
I noticed during your debut stream that you were really making an effort to speak Japanese.
頑張ってる中で見え隠れするこの「やばい部分」。
But behind that effort, your wild nature was clear for all to see.
見えてた！見えてたよね！
It was in plain sight. No, it wasn't!
めちゃ頑張ってるって思ったけど「ん？」って思うこともあって。そこが良い意味でやばくて面白かったんだけど。
I knew you were doing your best, but I also was like, “Uhh...” That was crazy in a good way, and I thought it was funny.
二人でスーパーバニーマンっていうゲームをコラボしたんだけど...
We also played Super Bunny Man together.
やってた！あのウサギのゲーム、やってたね！
Oh right, you did! We did indeed! Right! We did indeed! That bunny game...
やった時に本当に面白すぎて、初めて漏らすかと思って！
It was so funny that, for the first time in my life, I thought I was gonna wet myself.
やめなさいよ！アイドルですよ！
Cut it out! You're an idol!
こんな経験は初めてで、本当に楽しかった。
I've never experienced that before. It was really fun.
楽しかったよね。あやめ先輩とは、実はこの中では結構絡みが、残念ながら少なかったんじゃないかなと。
It was indeed. Unfortunately, me and Ayame-senpai haven't interacted much, compared to the others here.
もっとね、ぜひ遊びたかったんですけどね。
Yeah? That's right. Unfortunately. But from now on... That's quite unusual. I wanted to hang out.
本当に一つ謝りたくて。ココちゃんに、あの朝ココに出てくれませんか、ってお話を頂いた時があって、
Allow me to apologize for something here. Coco-chan asked me once if I'd like to appear in Morning Coco.
一年くらい前かな？
That was around a year ago, right?
そうですね、かなり前ですね。
Yeah, around that time.
「いいよ」って返して、提出したつもりで、全く返せてなかったっていう事件がありまして、
I replied like, “Sure!” But then I mistakenly thought I did my work and submitted it, while in truth I'd ended up ghosting her!
本当ごめんなさい！
I'm really sorry about that!
一年間ずっと気にしてたんですか！？
You were worried about it for a whole year?
提出したつもりで「あれ、朝ココ出ないな、メッセージどこだ？」って。
I thought I sent it, but then... “Wait, I'm not on Morning Coco... Wait, where are the messages?”
このタイミングでカミングアウト！？
You're spilling the beans now?
本当にごめんなさい。
I'm really sorry!
強制じゃないからいいですよ。でも本当にもっと絡む時間できれば欲しかったなっていう。
Don't worry, I wasn't forcing anyone. Just asking whoever was free to do it. But yeah, I wish I'd spent more time interacting with you.
心残りの一つではありますね。卒業後もぜひプライベートで遊んでくださいよ。
Yeah... That's one of the things I regret. I really regret it too. But let's hang out after I graduate!
ぜひ遊びましょう！ありがとうございます！
For sure, let's do it! I'll be waiting! Thank you!
チョコ先生！動きがなんか...
Choco-sensei... Sensei... Oh, you know... Her moves...! What's with those moves?
最初の印象は「ココ語」を作ってるやべえ奴だな、と。
Oh, Coco-sama... If we talk first impression... Your speech style was really something like... Coconese.
「ゲボかわドラゴン」とかもそうだけど、色々とやべえ奴だなと思いつつ。
Coconese? I thought that you are just creating your own language there. Stuff like “Gebokawa Dragon.” I just couldn't stop thinking that you were a weird one.
第一波のARKブームの時は全然分からなかったけど、みんなやってんなーみたいな感じだったんだけど。
Yeah. Then the first ARK boom happened. I had no idea about it before. I just casually tried it seeing how everyone else was playing it.
第二波でちょっとやってみたら、ドハマりしちゃって。
But when I gave it a real go during the second wave, I got really addicted to it.
廃人になった！
You really did! So you've noticed!
一緒にご飯行っても「いや、ARKがさー」みたいな。
Yeah. Even when we went to eat out together, I was like, “So, about ARK...” You could talk only about ARK!
「帰ってARKやらなきゃ」って帰っちゃいましたからね。
Just how addicted were you? She even bounced early, saying she had to go home and play ARK.
たくさん一緒にARK一緒に遊んでくれて本当にありがとうございました。先生！
Thank you for playing lots of ARK with me, Sensei!
こちらこそありがとうございました！
Thank you too!
最初とはその配信上で逆にあまり絡んだことないかもしれない。
To start off... I think we haven't interacted with each other on streams.
そうです。ですね。確かに。
You... are right! That's true!
意外そうかも。
That's quite unexpected.
配信以外で仲良くなりすぎた。
We spent too much time hanging out off-stream!
なんか知れっと会長の家で行われる
I just nonchalantly waltz into her house
パーティーとかには知れっと毎回いたりする。
if there's a party or something.
そうそう。スバルパイセンほぼいるんすよね。
Yeah, you're just... there all the time.
そうそう。なんか行って、で、なんかいつもココちゃんが、なんか
Yeah, I always barge in, and Coco-chan is always like,
「スバルパイセン、何飲み物にしますか？いっぱいありますよ」って言って
"Subaru-paisen, whatcha want to drink? I have tons of drinks!"
飲み物をね、毎回出してくれたりとか。
She always treats me drinks like that.
ココちゃんがそのタコパでオリーブオイルを重ねがけするっていう文化を...
At her takoyaki parties, there's a tradition to add olive oil...
オリーブオイル？
Olive oil?!
そうなんだよ。
Yeah!
そんなのたこ焼きに...
People do that?
カリカリにするんすよ。
They become crunchy!
へえー！
Huh?
めちゃめちゃ美味しくて。スバル、なんかそれ以降
It was so good, ever since then,
ホロライブメンバーとのタコパの時は毎回それしてるから、
I always use olive oil at takoyaki parties with other members.
ホロライブメンバーなんかみんなオリーブオイルかけるようになってて。
And now everyone in hololive likes olive oil on their takoyaki.
だから、もう卒業した後もね、絶対にまたタコパ開いてください。
So please hold more takoyaki parties even after you graduate.
遊びに行く。
I'll drop by.
行きます！
I surely will!
私も行きたい！
I wanna drop by too!
次はぜひ2期生の皆さんで遊びに来てくださいよ。
All of you 2nd Gens come hang out sometime!
あ、そうなの？
Right!
いいじゃん！
Nice idea!
たこ焼き！みんなで行こう！
Takoyaki! Let's do it!
焼くのは任せてほしいんで。
Leave the grilling to me!
やったー！
Woohoo!
カリカリに。
I'll make 'em nice and crunchy!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you!
今日はみんな、あの、来ていただいて本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you you all a lot for coming today!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you!
卒業してからも、仲良しでいてください。
I hope we can remain on good terms!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you!
もちろん！
Of course!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
またね！
See ya!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
またね！
See you!
ココちゃん好き！
Luv ya, Coco!
それでは、次はホロライブゲーマーズの先輩方に、来ていただきました。
So our next guests are the members of hololive Gamers!
先輩！
Hello!
イエーイ！
Yay!
なんか一人変なやついない？
There's some weird one mixed in.
何？門松いない？
What? There's a kadomatsu.
あ、本当だ。誰ですか？こんな人いましたっけ？
Ah, you're right! Who is this?
本当だって、お前のことなんだよ！
We're talking about you!
あれ？
Wh-huh?
間違えちゃった、これ場違いか、これ。
I thought this was a good idea. Was it not appropriate?
場違いだよ！
You stick out like a sore thumb!
間違えちゃった、これ。
I might've chosen the wrong outfit for this.
いやいやいや、気持ち悪い、気持ち悪い。
Stop it! That's creepy!
気持ち悪い、ココちゃん気持ち悪いですよ、これ。
Coco-chan, that's creepy. This is quite strange.
おかしい？でもね、今から脱げないのよ、これ。
Is it? But, y'know... I can't take this off anymore.
あ、脱げないの？そうなんだ。じゃあこのまま行くしかないですね。
I see... You can't? Yeah. We'll just have to continue like this.
申し訳ないんですけど。
I apologize for the trouble.
いや、今日はですね、皆さんに来ていただきまして。
I had you all come over today
視聴者の皆さんの前でね、こうやってお話しするっていうのが最後っていう意味になっちゃうので。
for one final conversation in front of the viewers.
これが最後に見ることができる私たちの話す姿になります。
This'll be the last time they get to see us talking.
見せつけたい、見せつけたい。
I wish we could show 'em more!
見せつけていきます。
Wanna keep showing off our interactions?
ドヤりたいのか。
You want to feel smug, huh?
なるほど。
I see.
まあ、ちょっと今までのなんか、桐生ココの思い出ですとか、
Well, if you have any memories with me
印象的だったことですとか、何かあったら
or anything that had an impact on you
教えてくれたっていいんですよ。
that you want to share, you can do that.
門松は、門松は、やっぱり、あのお、
I, Ms. Kadomatsu... For me...
朝ココがすごい印象的で。
Morning Coco was the most memorable thing.
あ、そうですね。
Ah, yeah.
そう、あの、裏社会講座とかね、すごい、
The underworld lessons segment, in particular...
ためになったよね。
It helped, right?
めちゃめちゃためになったんすよ。
Yeah, it was so useful.
実際なったから。ちょっと半分以上忘れちゃってるけど。
It actually helped. Though I've forgotten like half of what I learned...
でもすごい楽しかったし、
It was really fun,
本当に協力してもらえて...
and I was happy I could have you help—
「協力してもらえて」？
"Have you help"?
協力していただいたのは、あの、門松先輩ですよ。
You were the ones who helped me, Kadomatsu-senpai!
協力していただいたのは、先輩です。
You were the one helping me!
協力させてもらって、本当に楽しかったの。
It was fun being able to help you!
はいはい。ありがとね。
Yeah. Thanks.
先輩本当にありがとうございました。
No, thank you so much.
先輩がね、結構ね、あの、先輩、あの、裏社会講座でもうコーナー、
I, like... I made her an underworld lessons segment
私が勝手にね、人のコーナーを勝手に作るっていうのをやっちゃって。
without asking her.
いや、本当にめちゃめちゃ面白かった。
It was really fun.
台本も全部作ってくれたんだよね。
She wrote all the scripts for me.
あ、台本。
Oh, the scripts.
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, I didn't know that.
めちゃめちゃすごい。
That's amazing.
それはすごいね。
That's impressive.
すごいでしょ？
Isn't it?
もう取るだけですよ、こっちは。
I only had to record.
取るだけでもめんどくさいんすよ。
Recording is a pain too.
今思ったら結構先輩方にめんどくさいことさせてたなって。
Looking back, I made you all do some pain-in-the-ass things.
よくそんな新人ごときで、そんなことできたなって。
I'm wondering how I did that as a newbie.
今思ったら結構ね。
It's actually pretty shocking now.
いやあ、もうこれからも手伝うよ、裏社会講座。
I'll help you with your underworld lessons in the future too.
いいですか？
Really?
やろうかこれからも、ね、裏社会講座。
You're gonna keep helping?! We'll be holding more underworld lessons.
あー。あの...
Um...
皆さんに、見えないとこだね。視聴者の...
It's where the viewers can't see. For the viewers...
皆さんに、見えない裏のとこでね。裏社会講座を...
In the back where the viewers can't see, we'll hold more underworld lessons.
講座も。講座開こうぜ、そして。
Let's hold lessons.
やります、やります。
Yeah, we will.
真のね、ころねにね、直接ってことね。
Giving Korone direct lessons, huh?
あ、そう、そう。あー、そうそう。
Yeah. That's right.
やりましょう、やりましょう。
Let's do it!
澪しゃ、なんかある？
Mio-sha, how about you?
あ、うちはね、やっぱね...
As for me...
一番の思い出は...
My most memorable moment was,
なんかデビューして、まだそんなに経ってない時に...
not long after Coco's debut,
なんかその、ホロライブ全体で釣り大会をやった時あったでしょ？
we held a fishing competition for all hololive members.
あった、あったね。うん。
We did! Yeah.
あの時さ、めちゃくちゃさ、人さ...
We got so many members together back then.
あんなに集まると思わないぐらい、めちゃくちゃ人集まったじゃん。ホロライブメンバー。
We didn't think we'd have that many people!
うん。うん、うん。
Mhmm.
で、それでココちゃんは参加したいけどできない、みたいな...
And Coco-chan wanted to participate too, but couldn't.
感じになっちゃってて。うん。
Yeah.
でも当日、なんか分かんないけどパッションだけで...
But on the day of the competition, she found a way to join in through sheer passion.
なんかやってくれた、みたいな。
Yeah, that happened...
あったわー、そんなこと。
Yeah, I remember that.
一緒に釣りしてくれたことあったじゃん。
She was fishing too.
やっぱ、みんなが、皆さんが一緒に遊んでるの、やっぱ、あの...
I didn't want to be left out when all of you were together,
自分だけやっぱね、あの、参加しようと思っても...
but I couldn't get a hold of the game right away,
いきなり、あの、手に入れられるような状態ではなかったのでね...
even if I wanted to participate.
ま、でも手元にたまたまね、あの、近いゲームあったんで...
But I happened to have a similar game in hand.
それで皆で、あ、一緒に遊ぼうみたいな。なって。
So I figured I could join you all in spirit.
まあまあまあ。
Right, right.
同じようなもの釣れてたしね。
You were fishing up the same things, too.
結局ね、あの、ほぼ同じような感じだったんで。
Yeah. They were basically the same.
ゴミも釣れますし。いっぱい、紐も釣れますし。
I fished up trash, and a bunch of other things, too.
うわ、すごいじゃん。
Wow, amazing.
なので、まあ本気で、あれね、優勝を狙ってたんですよ、でも。
So, like... I was seriously trying to win.
おー、おー、おー。
Well, yeah.
こちらとしてもちゃんとね、あの、やってましたよ。あの、点数計算ちゃんとやったんだけど...
We were tallying your points on our side, too.
結果、まあ優勝ではなかった、っていうことだったね。
In the end, she didn't win.
惜しかったんだと思うんですよね、まあね。
I think I got pretty close, though.
惜しかったねー。
You were pretty close.
懐かしいなー。
That takes me back.
懐かしい。あれ、めっちゃ楽しかった。
Yeah. It was really fun.
ありがとうございます、いっぱい遊んでくれて。本当に。
Thanks for playing with me at the time. Really.
えーっと、おかゆ先輩もね、あのご迷惑いろいろおかけしました。
Um... I've caused Okayu-senpai a lot of trouble, too.
いやいや全然だよ。なんかね、あの、おかず事件がね...
Not at all! The Okazu incident, for one...
出ました、出ました、おかずね！ あれー！
The Okazu incident! There it is, Okazu!
でもあれね、思い返すと僕からね、言い出したことだからね。
But like, looking back, I was the one who said that first.
あれ、なんか私が無理やり、おかゆ先輩のこと、おかずって、そんなん言った感じ見えてますけど...
Did you guys notice how I was forced to call her "Okazu"?
あれ実際、そうなんですよ。先輩が自分から、自分から名乗っちゃってたんですから。私のせいじゃない。
She actually called herself that first. It wasn't my fault!
あー。あれは名乗っちゃってたのか。
She called herself that, huh?
そうですよ。おかゆ先輩。
Yeah.
でもね、もう願望じゃん。
She's wishing for it at that point.
願望？
Wishing?
おかずになりたいという真のね。
To be fap material?
バレちゃったか。
Yeah. That's what it means, right? To be fap material?
あら、あら、バレちゃった！ バレちゃった！
Oh my. I've been exposed.
それ言っちゃっていいんですか？
She's been exposed! Should you be saying that?
だめー！ だめですよ、だめ、だめ！
Nooo! That's not allowed!
だめだろ、だめだろ。
Is it? Is it not allowed?
だめてくださいよ、やめてくださいよ。私の卒業ライブですよ。なんてこと言ってるんですか、ちょっ、ちょっ！
No! Please stop! What the hell are you saying on my graduation stream?!
いや、でもやっぱココちゃんとのね、一番の思い出と言えば、みたいなとこあるからね。
But it is the most memorable thing I share with you, Coco-chan.
一番の思い出がおかず。あー。
The most memorable thing is... "Okazu"?
申し訳ないな。まあ、しょうがないのかな、ここまで来たら。
Yeah. In that case... I guess we can allow it. That's steamy.
ココちゃん、ココちゃんも、僕との思い出と言えば、やっぱおかずになっちゃいますね。そうですよね。
How about you? What was your most memorable thing with me?
なっちゃいますね。うふふふ、うふふ。ふふ。おかしいだろ、なっちゃうのかい！
It would be "fap material", huh? What? You too?! Seriously?
めちゃくちゃ楽しかったですからね。本当に。
It was really fun, after all.
端から見てもおかずだもん。
It's gotta be fap material for everyone else, too.
ん？ 何ですか？
Hmm? What do you mean?
端から見ても、おかずが思い出、みたいなとこあるよね。
It's that moment for everyone else, too. What do you mean by that?
あ、そういうことね。二人の思い出がね、そういうことね。
That thing must've been memorable for everyone, right? Ah, so that's what you mean.
びっくりした、びっくりした。違う意味かと思っちゃいましたけど。
That confused me. I thought she meant something else.
間違い、言っちゃった？
Did I... say something weird?
そうね。うん。
Yeah.
だから、それで、どういう風に繋げようか悩んじゃったもん。おかゆは主食だろ、とか言ったほうがいいのかな、とか。
I was wondering how to continue the conversation from that. Like, "Should I say, Okayu's some good ****in' food" or something?
それはちょっと違う意味に聞こえちゃいますかね。
That would mean something different entirely.
確かにね。傷がどんどん広がっていき。
Yeah. You'd have just made things worse.
やばい、やばい。
Close shave.
なので、あの、たったの、1年と、えー、7ヶ月くらいでしたけれども...
Anyway, we've only spent a year and 7 months together,
皆さんとね、こうやって楽しく過ごせて、私は本当に、あの、感謝しかありません。先輩方、皆さん。
but I'm thankful for all the fun moments we had.
あの、ま、今日卒業しちゃって、しまいますが...
I'll be graduating today,
どうか皆さん、あの桐生ココ、あの、忘れないでいていただきたいなって、あの、思います。
but I hope you all won't forget me!
忘れるわけないだろー！ バカー！
Of course we won't! We could never forget you, you idiot!
本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you for everything!
というわけで、本日来てくれました、ホロライブゲーマーズの先輩方でした。ありがとうございましたー！
Give it up for the members of hololive Gamers! Thank you for coming!
ありがとねー！ うぇーい！
Thank you for having us! Whooo!
3期生
3rd Generation
3rd Gen
それでは、えー次は...
And next up,
I'll be talking to all the members of the 3rd Gen
...3期生の先輩の皆さんとお話を、最後にさせていただきたいと思います！
...I'll be talking to all the members of the 3rd Gen one last time!
one last time!
先輩ー！
Hello!
うわああああああ！
Whoaaa!
最後とか言わないで！
Don't call it the last time!
悲しいー！やだー！
So sad! No way!
えっ、困ってる、困ってるよ。皆...
She's really flustered! Everyone...
She's really flustered!
...笑って笑って！笑顔で！
...let's all smile! She doesn't know how to react-o!
Let's all smile! She doesn't know how to react-o!
はい！笑顔で、笑顔でお願いますよ、ニコリ！
Yes, please! Let's do this with a smile!
まあ、あの、短い期間でしたけれども、えー...
Well, it was only for a short while, but...
Well, it was only for a short while,
...皆さんとたくさんね、あの絡むことができて、
...but I got to interact with you all loads.
but I got to interact with you all loads.
皆さんすごく優しくしていただいて、本当に、本当にいい思い出しかないんですけども、
You've all been so nice to me, and I have so many good memories with all of you,
まあその中でもちょっと、なんか、
but I was hoping that if you have
印象と言いますかありましたら、今日聞きたいななんて思ってるんですけども。
any particularly good memories or impressions, you might share them with us today.
やっぱ会長がさ、デビューした時さ、ぺこらたちにとってはさ、初めての後輩だったじゃん。
So like, when you first debuted, you were our first juniors, right?
そうですね。
Yeah, that's right!
で、衝撃だったよね！
And it gave me a shock-o!
ぺこら最初配信見た時に、印象がなんかもう凄すぎて、えっ、ヤバい奴来ちゃったぺこじゃんって思ったぺこ。
When I took a sneak peek at the first stream, I was just mindblown. I was like, "This girl's off her rock-o!"
いや船長も！凄かったよね、本当にね。
Yeah, me too! It was pretty amazing... like...
凄かったし、
It really was.
あの初めてだよ、なんかね、初配信で泣いたの初めて。泣いた。
And it was the first time I ever cried watching a debut stream, too.
泣いたの！？
You cried!?
最初のさ、
But the story with YAGOO
YAGOOとの下りめっちゃ感動したじゃん。ここで働きなさいって。
was so touching! "Work here!"
あれめっちゃ感動して、泣いちゃったんだよな。
It made me cry!
団長ー！
Noel!
感受性豊かか！
You're so emotional!
まあ私達はやっぱ、先輩なんですけど、一番何て言うか、先輩の中で一番後輩なんで、
Well, you guys came before us, but you were the newest out of all the others.
一番ちょっと何て言うか、絡みやすいというか、っていう感じだったんですよ、4期生からすると。
So you all were the easiest to break the ice with, you know? For all of us in the 4th Gen.
ああ、確かに。うん。
Oh, makes sense.
船長的には、ココさんのね、ご実家に...
For me, it'd be when I went over... t-to her place.
...遊びに行かせてもらって、お泊りして。
When you stayed over!
でそこでね、ココさんとね、もうビショビショのヌルヌルになりながら、ビクンビクンって。
And we got all dripping wet together. And all slippy-slippy!
And we got all dripping wet together.
ちょっと！言い方！言い方！
Oh, come on! Hey, phrasing!
BANされちゃうでしょ、配信できなくなっちゃう。
You want to get this stream banned?
え、でもしたよね、ココさん。ビショビショのヌルヌル。
But we did, didn't we? Get all dripping wet?
いや、真実なんですけどね、あの、真実なんですけど。
Yeah, it's true!
激しすぎて、ケツに青あざできました。あー。
We went at it so hard, my arse got all bruised.
あ、その青あざの写真送ってくれましたよね。大切に保存してます。
Then you sent me a photo of it. I've kept it safe and secure.
大切にしてください、これからも。
Yes. Please treasure it.
割れ目。
Your... butt crack.
Your... butt crack. What are they going on about?
何やってんだよ。
What are they doing?
え、写真ありがとうございました。卒業してからも大事にしてください、会長の尻。
Thank you for the picture. Please treasure it even after you graduate!
会長の尻！？尻の割れ目。
My arse! What?! Your butt crack...
パソコンのデスクトップにしときますね。
I'll set it as the wallpaper on my computer.
やめてー！やめてください。
Do not!
ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much! Do not!
他の皆は？
What about everyone else?
あ、でも団長もあれだね、オフの出来事の話なんだけど。
Actually, mine's about an offline occurrence too.
お？はいはい。
Oh? So right now,
そう、あの団長今あるそのノエスタが、あのカナココハウスの近くなんだよね。
my Noel Studio is pretty close to KanaCoco House.
そうですね。うん。
Yeah, it is.
それこそ、うん、あのココ会長にちょっとね、いいところを教えてもらって、そこから探したんだけど。
I managed to find a pretty nice place because Coco recommended it to me.
で本当に、うん、あの最初、本当に2週間ぐらいなんか何も荷物がない空白期間があった時に、
So right at the start, I didn't have anything at all for about the first two weeks.
その時に、もう電気もなくて、え、どうしようってなっちゃった時に、
I was sweating because I didn't even have any lights!
そのカナココハウスからココ会長の、なんか昔使ってた電気を借りて、
But she brought me one of her old lights from KanaCoco House
「え、じゃあちょっと引っ越し終わった後に返すね」って言って半年経つんだけど、未だにリビングで使ってます。すいません！
and was like, "You can give it back after you're done moving," but it's been half a year and I'm still using it in my living room. I'm sorry!
借りパクだ！カリパクだ！ありがたくカリパクしてんぜ！
You never gave it back! You kept it! You totally just kept it!
全然いいっすよ。逆にちょっと卒業の記念にココさんだと思って、持っていってください。
That's perfectly fine! Now that she's graduating, maybe you can keep it as a memento of her.
そうなんだよ。ココさんが輝いてるんだよ、団長のリビングで。大事にします。
Coco's shining in my living room! I'll take good care of her.
うん。大事にしてください！
Yeah. Take good care of her!
すげーダサいやつなんですけどね、あの。昔ながらのなんか紐がついとるやつ、
It's a really tacky light, though. It's one of those lights with a string dangling down.
紐がついた、あのカチカチってやるやつ。昭和感溢れる。
O-One where you pull the string and it goes, "click, click." One of the old school ones.
ちょっとあのダサすぎてカナココハウスでは使えなかったんでクローゼットにしまってたんですけど、団長がね、緊急事態で部屋真っ暗だって言うんで。
It was too tacky for KanaCoco House, so I'd put it away in the closet, but she desperately needed a light...
大事にします。
I'll treasure it.
大事にしてください。差し上げます。全然。
Yes, please do! You can have it! It's all yours!
やったー！やったぜー！
Yay!
あの捨て方とか分からなかったんでちょうどいい。
I didn't know how to get rid of it, anyway.
捨てないよもう！そんな、そんな事言わないでー。やめてー。
There's no way she'll throw it out! Please stop...
でも本当にね、オフでもね、皆さんお会いしましたから結構。
But really, we did all meet in person quite a lot.
私もオフでの思い出。
Mine's an offline thing, too.
おお、るしあ。うんうん。
Rushia!
やっぱね、やっぱ一番はなんかこう、引っ越しのきっかけ。
For me, it was how she spurred me on to move.
そうだよね、るしあちゃん、ずっと悩んでたもんね、るしあね。
That's right! You couldn't decide whether to move or not.
すごい積極的に物件をポンポンポンポン送ってくれて、
Well, she kept finding all these places and sending them to me,
そう、で、なんか近くにね、こう、いるんだなって思って安心するじゃん。で頼りになるし、
and it was also really reassuring knowing that she'd live nearby. I'd be able to get her help with things.
そうですね。うんうん。
Yeah, it is.
すごい引っ越して、ですぐ引っ越したその日に、ココちゃんとかなたんと...
So I ended up moving, and the day that I moved, I met up with Coco-chan and Kanatan...
ココちゃんかなたんと会って…
I met up with Coco-chan and Kanatan...
何笑ってんの？
What are you laughing about?
今の羽振りなの？今のなんか
Was that some kind of... thing just now?
速かったな
You were so fast!
今のなんか羽振り半端なかったっすね
That move just now was incredibly sharp.
秘密！
It's a secret!
秘密！？気になるのちょっと
A secret? That makes me more curious.
そうそれで、
Then after that,
それでまあね、それからココちゃんとかかなたんが連絡くれるようになって、
they would often contact me,
それでココちゃんがこう、遊びにおいでよみたいなね、かなココハウスに良く呼んでくれて、
and Coco-chan would often invite me to go hang out at KanaCoco House.
たくさんタコパとかしたよね
We had lots of takoyaki parties, didn't we?
よかったねー
That's so nice!
フレア先輩もね、あの、遊びに来ていただいて
You should come visit too, Flare-senpai.
行きたい行きたい、いや、約束したもんね
I totally want to! We promised, right?
約束しましたもんね、行こうね
Yeah, we did!
行こうね
You'd better be ready for me.
お泊りも来ていただきましたからね
You did stay the night once too!
うん
Yeah.
いや、マジでさ、ココちゃんのさ、マットレスがさ、
But like, what really left an impression on me was that the mattress
自分の自宅で使ってるやつよりも、お客様用の方が高かったのが結構印象的で
Coco-chan has for her guests is even more expensive than the one I use for my own bed at home.
おおー
Oh!
ココさん優しいな、思いやりだ
Coco-san's so kind! So thoughtful!
そんなね、みなさんがいらっしゃるところをね、
Well, there's no way that I can
そんな安っすいあのマットに寝かせるわけにいかないじゃないですか！
let all of you sleep on a cheap mattress!
大先輩！優しい！大先輩！
You're all my seniors! You're so thoughtful!
ふかふかでした
It was so soft.
ふかふかをね、ちょっとあの用意させていただいて
Yeah. I put a really soft one in there.
はい、あ、本当にお世話になりました
Thank you so much for everything!
私はあー、もういなくなっちゃいますが、
I won't be here anymore...
でもね、あの本当楽しい思い出しかないので、
But I really did have a lot of good times,
笑顔でお別れができます
which is why I can leave with a smile today.
私たちの4期生、あの、あと4人ね、
The four other members of 4th Gen
残りますから、
will still be here, though,
まあ、あの、優しくしてやってくださいよ
so please continue to treat them well.
もちろんですよ、優しくしますよ
Yeah! Of course we will!
優しくしますよ
We'll be kind.
本当に本日はありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for joining me today!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you for having us!
私も3期生の先輩方、みんな大好きです！
I love all of you 3rd Gens!
何その動き！
What's up with that dance?!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
またね、ココちゃん！
See you again, Coco-chan!
またねです！
See you!
それでは、次は後輩のね、5期生が来てくれました！
Now then, next up are my juniors! The 5th Generation!
5期生のみなさーん！
Hey, 5th Gen girls!
ちーす！会長！
'Sup, Chairman!
ちーす！
'Sup!
いぇーい！
Yay!
近い！
So close!
後輩ですね、これね、
These are my juniors. So...
動きがすごい！
Your moves are amazing!
えっ？
Huh?
やっぱ先輩の動きはちげえわ
They're really on another level.
やっぱ先輩ですから。これぐらい動けるように
Because I'm your senior.
先輩になるとなるんですね。
You're able to move like this when you become someone's senior.
みなさんも先輩になればね
So when you do...
先輩だもんな、なるほど
Because you're our senior, I see.
そう、先輩ですよ、知ってました？
Yeah, I'm your senior. Didya know that?
知ってた！
No!
ちーす！ちーす！
'Sup! 'Sup!
先輩だぞー！
I'm your senior!
やめてください！
Please stop!
もぐら叩きみたいになってて
What is this, whack-a-mole?
今日はね、5期生のみなさんとね、
Now I'll be talking with the 5th Generation.
ちょっと座り方がかっこ悪かったんですけど、
The way I just sat down was kind of lame.
まあ、5期生のね、
Anyway, this is, well...
一応ね、話す最後の機会ということで
It's officially our last chance to talk together.
あ、そっか。最後なんだ。
Ah, right. The last time.
みなさんとお話できたらいいなって思いまして、来ていただきました！
I thought it'd be nice if we could all have a chat, so here we are!
思い出なんかもね、作る時間が一番やっぱ短かったんで、みなさんとは
You guys were, well, the ones I had the shortest amount of time to make memories with.
本当ですよ
I know, right?!
みなさんとは数ヶ月ですからね
I only had a few months with you guys.
私がホロライブにいた時間自体が1年と7ヶ月ぐらいで
My time in hololive was about a year and seven months.
みなさんがデビューしたのは8月なので11ヶ月ですね
And you guys debuted in August. So about eleven months ago.
1年も経ってない
Not even a year!
だったんですね！
That's right!
経ってないんですよ
Not even a year.
短いなー
That's not long.
最後ですし、ぶっちゃけちゃって印象なんかも言っちゃってもいいんじゃないですか？
since this is the last time, maybe you could share your honest impressions of me and stuff!
え、じゃあ第一印象とか言います？
Oh? How about our first impression, then?
第一印象！
First impression!
聞きましょう。一番大事、マスト！
Okay, let's hear them. That's the most important. A must!
あのね、初配信の時の最初の入りのアニメ、手描きアニメみたいなやつ
During your debut stream, you had that hand-drawn animation at the beginning.
すごかった！
That was amazing!
あれがめっちゃ印象に残ってて、うんうん
That really stuck with me. I thought it was great.
ねねがデビューする時もああいう最初からインパクトのある女になりたいなと思って
It made want to become someone who could make an impact like that on her debut, too.
女に？
A woman?
失敗した
But I didn't.
失敗した！？
You didn't?!
「心配したのかな？」って来ないっすか？
Doesn't it occur to you like, "Did she worry about us?"
え？本当に？
Huh? Really?
全然心配してないと思いますけど...
I don't think you were worried at all, though...
イェーイ！
Yay!
皆さんにはそういうふうに印象に残ったお話を聞いたの本当初めてなんで、ちょっと嬉しいです。
Well... this is my first time hearing how I've left a mark on you guys. It's making me a little happy to hear.
じゃ、ラミィちゃん！ラミィちゃん、ラミィちゃん、最後ラミィちゃん。
Okay, Lamy-chan! Lamy-chan, Lamy-chan, go next.
ラミィはもう、ココ先輩のことプレスリリースから見てるんで。
Well, I first started watching you from your press release.
プレスリリース？！
Since my press release?!
あなたの第一印象いつからですか、それ！
When exactly is your first impression, then?!
プレスリリースですよ！
From then!
いや、とにかく凄かった！台風のような感じでプレスリリースから凄いインパクトがあったし！
Anyway, it was incredible! Your impact starting with your press release was like a typhoon!
それだけで身長がめちゃめちゃ高くて！
Just for the fact that you were so tall!
あ、それな！
Oh, that!
それな。
That's true.
凄かったし。
It was amazing.
初配信のインパクトも凄かったし。
And your debut stream was very impactful, too.
とにかくホロライブに完全に新しい風が吹きまくってた。
Anyway, it was like you were a complete breath of fresh air for hololive.
ビュービューしてたね。
She blew right in.
褒められちゃってますね、これ。
Oh! She's really praising me.
でもココ会長が入ってだいぶ変わったよね、その今までの流れが本当に。
But you really did shake things up when you joined.
俺らもさ、やっぱり5期生としてデビューしてわかるけど、新人としてデビューして、
After we debuted as the 5th Generation, we can understand now how incredibly hard you had to work as a newcomer
先輩たちにあさココとかを協力してもらうの、どれだけ大変か入ってみてわかるじゃない？
to get your seniors to collaborate with you on Morning Coco and things like that.
労力の使い方とかね。
And how you made sure to be low-risk when featuring them.
いや、本当に。初めてできた...なんていうか...
Well, you guys were my first juniors, so how do I say...
遠慮なしにイジっていい後輩だったのでね、私にとって。
I could tease you without any hesitation.
確かに。
Certainly.
私はあさココとかで先輩をイジってきたりはしたけど...
I mean, I teased my seniors in Morning Coco, too.
「顔面爆発したり頭剃ったりしていいですか？」って...
But I had to ask like, "Excuse me, can I use this image of you with your face exploding?"
許可制だ。
So you had to...
そう、許可を求めたりしてたんです。
Yeah, I had to ask them for permission and stuff.
けど後輩に関しては「もういいか！」と思って。
But for you guys, well, whatever!
あんま聞かずに適当に爆破しちゃったりとかして。
I could just blow you guys up without asking first.
そうだった。
I see.
初コラボで会長に7回くらい爆破されましたもんね。
My first collab was with you, and you really did blow me up. About seven times!
爆発したね！
I did, didn't I?
あの時はお互いに「どこまでいいんだろ」ってギクシャクしてたし。
Back then, we were both really awkward, like... "Oh man, how far can I take it?"
でも今はこうして普通に話せてるし。
But now, we can talk together normally like this.
ちょうど馴染んできた時だったのに...
We all just got friendly with each other.
突然の卒業、すまんの！
So I'm sorry for graduating so suddenly!
会長ーーー！！
Chairman!
許す！許さねえ！許した！
I forgive you! Unforgivable! I forgive you!
あさココやってた時は、一番後輩の立場でやってたじゃないですか。
When you were streaming Morning Coco, you were at the bottom of the totem pole, right?
もちろんね。
Absolutely.
それでもホロメンを繋ぐハブとして機能してましたよね。
But even then, you really brought people together. You were like a hub for all the hololive members.
5期生も会長みたいにならないとね、って思ってます。
It makes me think that we in the 5th Gen need to be a little more like you.
マジレス。素晴らしい。
A srs bzns answer.
本当だ、そうだ。そうだ、そうだ。
But I agree! That's right.
助けて会長！時計が止まっちゃう！
Help us, Chairman! While the clock's running out!
助けて会長、俺たちどうしたらいい？
Chairman, what should we do?
アドバイスありますか？
Do you have any advice?
アドバイスを！
We need advice!
思い切って！
Just go for it!
先輩たちは皆さん優しいって知ってると思うけど。
I think you already know, but all the hololive members are really nice.
皆さん話しやすくて優しい方々だから。
They're really nice and approachable.
私の時は特別というか、ある意味好きに暴れられたけど。
Well, it was a bit different for me at that time. I was able to run wild a bit.
今の皆さんとはちょっと状況が違うかもしれないけど。
That might be a little different for you guys now.
皆さんなりのやり方で視聴者さんを楽しませてほしいな。
I want you guys to entertain your viewers in your own special way.
それが先輩からの最後のアドバイスかな。
I suppose that is my final advice to you.
うわあああ！ギリギリ攻めていきます！！
We'll continue pushing that envelope!
重いよ...！
The gravity...!
楽しく、楽しくやればいいんじゃないかな？
If you just have fun with it, it's all good, right?
私も楽しかったからやってただけだしね。
That's all I really did. Just had fun with it!
いずれ新しいメンバーも入ってきて、君たちも先輩になる。
You'll eventually see new members pop up, too.
その時にどう後輩を導くかは、君たち次第だ。そういうわけ。
And how you lead them... well, that's up to you. That's how it is.
無様な姿は見せるなよ？
Don't embarrass yourself, okay?
イェーイ！
Yay!
わかりました！
Understood!
了解！
Got it!
見ててください！
Please watch us!
イェーイ！
Yay!
俺らの頑張りを見ててください！
Please watch us work hard!
叫びすぎだよ！
God damn, no need to bellow!
それでは、5期生の皆さんでした！ありがとうございました！
Give it up for the 5th Gen!
来てくれてありがとうね！
Thank you so much for coming!
イェーイ！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you!
愛してる！
I love you!
EN
はい！
Okay!
ではここからは、ホロライブ EN の後輩どもに来てもらいましたよ！
Now I've got the members of hololive English here!
皆さん！Thank you for coming to
Guys! Thank you for coming to
my 桐生会事務所！
my Kiryu Group Headquarters!
hololive English の皆、イエーイ！
hololive EN peeps! Yay!
Hello!
※がうる・ぐらはスケジュールの都合により同期録音となりました
*Gawr Gura was recorded asynchronously due to scheduling.
Guys! Thank you for coming to my graduation stream!
Oh, don't feel sad!
Of course! Of course!
Any time for you, Senpai.
ありがと、来てくれて。
Thanks for being here!
今日はね、あの私の、え、卒業ということで、色々とね...
Today, well, it's my graduation.
...あの後輩なんでね、ちょっと私と一緒に過ごす時間は皆さんよりかは少なくなってしまいましたけど...
And my juniors here, well, haven't had as much time with me as everyone else,
...色んな印象とかあったら聞いていこうかなと思います。
but I'd like to hear what your memories of me are like.
So guys! Well, you guys... as you guys know, I am graduating, but umm...
What did you guys think about Kiryu Coco?
You have any memories?
Iconic!
Iconic?
An absolute icon.
Really? Was I?
And literally the reason we are here.
We wouldn't be here without you, Senpai. We freakin' love you!
Oh god, really?
How about you, Kiara-chan?
Uh, in the beginning, I thought that... when I saw your debut stream...
I thought that you were a really creative and funny dragon.
But also an insanely hard worker from the beginning, because you did stuff like Morning Coco.
And I thought that was like... anything you did was really interesting.
But one thing that I was worried about is if it's not difficult to speak when your tongue is always sticking out!
True!
At that time my mouth was like always open, I know! I remember.
Yeah!
And my tongue was always sticking out, and I was...
It looked like I was speaking with my tongue out always. It was like...
(Coco speaking in tongue)
Yeah!
Plus, I kinda sounded like I was like—you know, I had the... well, I do right now, but a nasal voice.
It kinda really looked like I was really talking with my tongue out.
But I wasn't! I wasn't! It just looked like that.
How about you, Ina-chan?
Ina-chan! Thank you for coming!
Thank you for having us!
I know we didn't have much time to interact with each other, but, you know...
We're BFFs, right?
Yeah.
Well... how could I forget your legendary 3D debut stream?
Your dance moves just... wow. Captivating. Legendary.
Aw, thank you! Thank you so much!
みんな意外と私の配信見てくれて、嬉しいなー。
They all watch my streams more than I thought. That makes me happy!
Amelia! Thank you for coming!
Thank you for having me!
Now that Ina mentioned your birthday stream, I remember we were all watching your 3D debut,
I think together in Discord around that time.
And I remember when you flipped!
You did a flip and we were like, "Did she just do a flip? What the hell?!"
It was insane!
You guys wanna see it again?
Really?!
Yes!
Can I do it? Can I?
Oh yeah, let's go!
Whoa!
That's so awesome!
I can do it any time.
I can't do that. I can't even do a handstand. Damn!
What?!
みんな私の配信見ててくれて！
They've all been watching my streams!
そしてさらにね、私のこうやって、あの記念配信とかも実は裏でDiscordとかで一緒に見てくれてたんですね。
And they were watching my celebration streams all together in Discord.
Well, I wish I had more time to, you know... do collabs and do funny stuff with you guys.
And I really regret that I couldn't interact with you guys in 3D.
Yeah...
That would have been so fun.
I wanted to dance with you.
Yeah, I wanted to dance with you guys! I wanted to dance with you guys!
Calli-chan!
Calli-chan, we played games together.
We kinda interacted...
well, how many times was that, like... Gosh, like three? Three collab streams?
Gosh, like three? Three collab streams?
Yeah!
Sometimes playing on the side, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
I remember I thought your cover of
"Shitsureishimasu ga, RIP" was so amazing,
"Excuse Me, But Could You Please RIP?" was so amazing,
and I got so excited every time I saw it!
Yeah!
I have one regret.
I just couldn't complete that fast from that...
失礼しますが、RIP...
Excuse me, but RIP...
It is so fast.
I can't pronounce it right.
I mean, that's okay.
Even I can't. It's written to be that way,
but you know what?
I thought your spirit was so fantastic.
I couldn't help but have a big smile
on my face watching you sing that.
Thank you!
You've got the makings of a great rapper, Senpai.
Can I continue practicing that
"Shitsureishimasu ga, Rest in Peace"...
"Excuse me, but Rest in Peace"...
uh, that "RIP" after my graduation?
Absolutely!
Of course you can, Senpai. Any time that you want.
It's so amazing.
Thank you so much!
I wanna say, like, you...
You were really a big inspiration to me.
When I was gonna join—
when I was thinking about auditioning for hololive,
I was really nervous at first, kinda wondering,
"Oh, am I gonna be able to kinda like..."
I mean, kinda have a bit of a big personality.
But you just kind of, you do what you want.
And it really made me feel like,
"Oh, wow! I wanna try and do that, then."
So I just wanna say thank you from the bottom of my heart.
Please! Please, you guys!
I appreciate you, Senpai.
It's a message from me to you guys.
To the "kouhais" of EN:
To the juniors of EN:
Please, please don't stop being yourself.
Please don't stop trying and
trying to do, you know, new stuff.
Challenging! Please, do not stop doing that.
And don't forget about me ever! Okay?
Never, Senpai! We'll never forget you, ever!
How could we forget you?
Oh no! Someone just disappeared again!
Oh no, Kiara!
Overwhelmed by emotions!
The chicken flies the coop again!
キアラちゃん時々涙を抑えるために消えちゃいますが...
Kiara-chan disappears once in a while to control her emotions...
それでも、みんなとこうして出会えて、
Even so, getting to meet you all like this,
一緒に遊ぶ時間はちょっと少ないですけど、
though our time playing together was short,
それでもたくさんENのメンバーと仲良くなれて良かった。
I'm still glad I got to become friends with the EN members.
これからもずっと友達だと思ってます。
I'll forever think of you all as my friends.
それではENの皆さん...
Now then, EN peeps...
Thank you! Thank you for coming! 来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you for coming! Thank you for being here!
Bye-bye, guys!
Thank you!
Thank you, Senpai! Goodbye!
We love you, Coco!
Don't you forget about me!
Don't you ever!
I'll miss you!
Kiryu Group forever!
Bye-bye! Goodbye, Senpai!
はい！それでは！
And coming up next,
ENのがうる・ぐらちゃんに来ていただきました！
we've got EN's Gawr Gura-chan!
Thank you for coming, Gura-chan!
ぐらちゃん！ぐらちゃん！ぐらちゃん！Hey, Gura-chan!
Gura-chan! Gura-chan! Gura-chan! Hey, Gura-chan!
Coco-senpai!
Hiii!
Thanks for coming.
Thank you for having me!
You're all by yourself!
Yeah!
Well, uhm...
So, this is my graduation live today.
And I wanna know what...
Well, we had some memories together, didn't we?
Yeah, yeah!
Well, I hoped we had more,
but yeah, we had memories...
Like, uh... Usada Construction Summer Festival!
Yeah, you couldn't find me!
I was lost.
It was fun playing with you, so...
Yes.
Gura-chan, what do you think about
idol Kiryu Coco?
I think Kiryu Coco is amazing!
Kiryu Coco idol is amazing!
Aww!
Yes, I have a obsessive yet healthy
curiosity and obsession with...
Wait, obsessive...
Kiryu Coco-senpai idol. Yes!
Yes, I am an idol!
And I think you are an idol too!
Well...
If you say so... Oh, oh, oh?
Gura-chan, well, I really wanted to play with you more.
It was... It was a... It was a short time.
I wanted to collab with you more.
I wanted to play games with you more.
And I regret that I didn't have time to do that.
Gura-chan, how 'bout you?
I wish we... I wish we could have played,
like, ARK together.
Oh, ARK?
Yeah!
Do you like ARK?
I've never tried it,
but I wanted to try it with you! Yeah!
You should and...
Gura-chan, promise me right now
you will play ARK with the hololive members. Promise me!
We're playing ARK, everybody!
Yeah! Let's goooo!
So thank you, Gura-chan, for coming!
Bye, Gura-chan!
Thank you, thank you! Thank you!
では、次はなんとこちらの事務所に初めてインドネシア組のみんなが来てくれました！
Now up are first-time visitors to the HQ, the Indonesian members!
こんにちは、ホロライブIDの皆さんです！
Hello, everyone from HoloID!
イェーイ！
Yay!
もうね、全員勢揃いですよ。こんなことありますか、皆さん？
Wow, it's the whole lineup! Can you believe it?
今日はね、私の卒業ライブに来てくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you all for coming to my graduation stream today.
悲しくならないでくださいね。
Please don't be sad!
まあね、あの、ID組の皆さんとはね、ちょっとまあ、絡む機会は少し、まあ、少なかったかもしれないですけど、
I didn't have much of a chance to interact with the ID members.
でもね、あの、一緒に遊んでくれたり、まあちょっと残念ながら遊べなかった子たちもいたんですけども、
I did get to hang out with some of you... but unfortunately not all of you.
皆さん、私の、第一印象ってありますか？
So, what were your first impressions of me?
What did you think about Kiryu Coco?
第一印象ですか？
Our first impressions?
そうそうそう。
Yeah.
誰から行きます？
Who wants to go first?
あ、じゃあ、リスちゃん！
Then how about Risu-chan?
おー、私からね。OK。
Starting with me, okay.
I think of Kiryu Coco as Superdragon!
スーパードラゴン！イェーイ！
Superdragon, yay!
Always brave and cheerful, yes.
I always look up to Coco-senpai!
ココ先輩！
Coco-senpai!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
Chairman Coco!
会長！ありがとうございます、リスちゃん。
Chairman! Thank you, Risu-chan.
リスちゃんとは、あの、まあね、ちょっと二人でいろいろ配信したりっていう機会がなかなかなかったのでね、
Risu-chan and I didn't really get a chance to stream together.
もっと仲良くなりたかったですけどね。ね、リスちゃん？
But I wanted to get friendlier with her. Right, Risu-chan?
うーん。
Mhm!
ムーナは？
How about Moona?
First impression of Coco-senpai, uh... is cool! So cool!
ホントに？ムーナより？
Really? More than you?
Yeah!
ムーナの方がクールだよ。
I think Moona's cooler.
And so nice! I love you.
ムーナはね、あのID組で唯一二人でね、Reddit Shitpost Reviewを一緒にね、出てくれたんで、
Moona was the only one from the ID group I got to do a Reddit Shitpost Review with!
まあホントに、実は、本当はみんなとやりたかったんですけどね。
I really wanted to be able to do it with all of them, though!
時間が取れなくてごめんね。でもたくさん、たくさんね、遊んでくれましたからね。
Sorry for running out of time. But we had a lot of fun.
イオフィちゃん！
Iofi-chan!
はい！
Yes!
もっと遊びたかったですよね。イオフィちゃんとも。
I wanted to hang out with you more. Me too!
お話しとかお絵かきとかしたいね！
I want to talk with you and draw with you!
ねえ。卒業してからでもね。
Yeah! Maybe after I graduate.
どんなんだろうね、第一印象って言えば一言で言えば、
Well, my first impression, if I had to put it simply...
やばいかな？
"What the hell!" I guess?
やばいって何だよ！
What's that supposed to mean?!
やばい、この人面白いとか、やばい、美人とか、そういうやばいです。
Like "What the hell! She's so funny!" or "What the hell! She's beautiful!" That's what I mean.
そんなやばい。良い方のやばい。
So in a good way. A good "what the hell".
セクシーな方の。
In a sexy way.
そうそうそう。この人やばいセクシー、やばい面白いとか。
Right! "What the hell! She's sexy!" "What the hell! She's funny!"
やべー、セクシー。そうそうそう。
"What the hell! Sexy!" Yeah!
ホントですか？でも褒められちゃってるから嬉しいです。イオフィちゃんとももっと一緒に遊びたかったな。
Really? Well, you're praising me, so I'm glad to hear it. I wish we could have hung out more, Iofi-chan.
オリー！
Ollie!
オリー、このやろう。
Ollie, you SOB...
このやろうって！
SOB...?!
When I first saw Coco-senpai, I had the same thought as Iofi-senpai. I thought you were a sexy mama!
ありがとうございます、オリーちゃん。卒業してからも仲良くしてくださいね。
Thank you very much, Ollie-chan! Let's stay close after I graduate!
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah!
さて、アーニャ！
And now Anya!
はい！えーっと、第一、第一印象ですね。
Yes! My first impression, huh.
デビューの前からでも結構私朝ココ見てて。
Before I debuted, I used to watch Morning Coco quite a bit.
おっ、中毒者！
Oh! An addict!
Yeah, I've been watching Morning Coco since the OG days, I think!
いえいえいえ。
Yeah, yeah!
So my first impression of you was from that. And I thought you were quite insane.
お、ヤバイ、クレイジー？！
Oh god, she-crazy?!
Crazy! Insane! But, you know, in good meaning, in good ways.
ありがとうございます、アーニャ。良い意味で。良い意味で！
In a good way. Ah, thank you so much, Anya. In a good way!
雰囲気とかからも。
Your presence in general.
雰囲気？！
My presence?!
覇気？！
染み出てた？！
Did I ooze it?!
好きなくせに！
You like it!
優しいですしもう。
And you're kind.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you!
もっと遊びたかったですね。
I wanted to hang out with you more.
そう、アニャちゃんはもう本当に多分一番ちょっと遊べる機会が、あの、取れなかったんじゃないかと思って凄くね。
I think you were the one I had the least chance to spend time with.
心残りが、ありますね。アニャー！
That's a big regret of mine, Anya!
ありますね。
Me too.
ねぇ。卒業してからこっそりじゃあ沢山遊びましょうね。
Let's have a ton of fun in secret after I graduate, then!
遊びましょう。
Let's do that!
やった！
All right!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you!
そして、おい、ターキー！
And now... hey! Turkey!
ええ？！何？！
What?!
Coco-senpai! My first impression of you is...
that you are so smart in marketing your products.
You're very good at it. Very nice.
Your commercials, too!
They're very, very good.
And as I thought, you have a very nice... very nice moves! And a very big... big...
Big personality, yeah!
ありがとう！本当にありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you so much!
インドネシア語教えてくれて、
Thank you so much for teaching me Indonesian,
文化を教えてくれて、
and teaching me your culture,
ターキーの焼き方教えてくれて、
and teaching me how to cook turkey,
ジャン***の言い方教えてくれて、
and teaching me how to say jan***!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
やばいよ！
What the hell!
大丈夫。とても良い学…学生、生徒。はい。
It's okay. You're a very good gaku... gakusei... student. Yes.
ガクステューデント！
Gakustudent!
ガクステューデントと、本当ね、最後に沢山思い出をね、あの、二人でのインドネシア語教えてもらう配信でも作れたんじゃないかなって思っています。
I feel like the two of us made a lot of memories in that last stream where you taught me Indonesian.
インドネシア組のみんな！
Indonesian members!
本当に沢山の思い出と、あとね、仲良くしてくれた楽しい思い出をありがとうございました。
Thank you for all the fun memories and for becoming friends with me!
ありがとうございました！サンキューID！ホロライブインドネシア、エブリバディ！
Thank you so much! Thank you, ID! hololive Indonesia, everybody!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとう、エブリバディ！みんなありがとうございました！
Thank you, everybody! Thank you all so much!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
4期生
4th Gen
それでは、次は、同期の四期生ですね。
And finally, we have my 4th Gen mates
最後に、来てもらいました！
to cap it all off!
事務所に呼び出しだーい！
They're all here at HQ!
同期の、おい！おら！
Here they ar—Yo, hey!
やったー！
Yaaaay!
うわーい！
Woohoo!
呼び出された！
We're here!
面談か？これは。
Is this an interview?
わーい！
Yay!
何ここ…？
What's this place...?
なんだこの空気は？！
What's with this mood?!
ちょっと良い椅子用意したから。な。
I have good seats for you guys.
初めて来たここ. 良い椅子？
It's our first time here. Good seats?
初めて？
First time?
初めて。ようこそようこそ。
First time. Welcome! Make yourselves at home.
桐生会事務所よ、どう？
Whaddya think of the HQ?
なんか、これ、ルーナに合わないんじゃないの、この椅子。
I don't think this chair's for me...
お気に召さないようだな。
It seems she doesn't like it.
結構文句出てますけど。
We already have complaints!
うるせえな！
Oh, shut it, will ya?
却下！
Denied!
うるせえな、もう。
Shut yer traps.
ブーブーブー。パイプ椅子にするぞお前ら。
Shooed off! This, or steel chairs?
やめてー！
Cut it out!
感謝しろ。
Be thankful, then!
今日はね、そしてあのね、こういう風に話すのは最後になる、
Yeah... today will be the, uh... this'll be the last time we can talk like this,
わけだ. 卒業、なんだね. 卒業ライブだよ. 今日は卒業ライブの配信。
since today's my graduation event and all.
というわけでね. 最後にやっぱり四期生の、同期のみんなと話しておきたいなと思いまして。
So I thought, why not have a talk with all of 4th Gen?
今まで先輩とか話聞きましたけど、まあね、
I've talked to the others too,
呼び出しよお前らは。
but yeah... I've summoned y'all now.
呼び出されちゃった…
We've been summoned...
特別だからな。
You're special to me!
何されるんですか？
What are you gonna do to us?
嫌だ怖い帰る！
I'm scared! I'm going home!
何かされたいんかい？
You expecting something?
えっ？
What...?
されてるの今. ニヤニヤしやがって。
Your grin gives it away.
喜んでるわ。
She's enjoying this!
何してくれるんだ. へへへ。
I wonder what she'll do... Hehehe.
まあちょっとした思い出とか、なんかそういうの語る…
I'm feeling like looking back, talking about some memories...
まあ何でもいいけど. 何でもいいですけどね。
Well, it could be anything, really!
色々ね、話したいこといっぱいあるよね。
Could be anything. There's a lot we could talk about, yeah.
無い！
None!
嘘でしょ、ちょっと。
You serious?!
以上. 無しかよ。
That's a wrap!
マジかよ？！
You sure about that?
カットカットだよ今のはもう。
Cut that part out! That didn't count!
まあまあ. いやだからまあね. そうね。
Well, well... I mean... yeah...
改めてって言うと。
Now that you mention it...
そうだね。
That's right.
なんか緊張しちゃうなと思うけど。
I got pretty nervous there.
いや、みんなでね。
Yeah, everyone here...
手紙？
A letter?
ああそう、今日はね. 四期生。
Yeah, everyone in 4th Gen
みんなちょっと手紙を書いてきました。
Yeah, everyone in 4th Gen wrote letters
ココに贈る言葉をね。
containing our messages for you, Coco.
あ、なんか持ってるね。
Oh, ya holding something.
そうなんだよ、実はね。
Right.
持ってないけども。
I'm not holding it yet, though.
持って…？
Holding...?
ジャーン！
Ta-da!
おお！
Whoa!
お手紙を、お手紙を書いて参りましたので。
It's a letter! We all wrote our own letters!
それを読んだりしつつ。
And we'll be reading them
思い出話をしたりしつつな感じでね、行きたいと思います。
while looking back at everything that we've done together.
はい！
Yep.
誰から読む？
Who do we start from?
誰から読む？これ。
Who wants to start?
誰から行こっか。決めてないよね？
Who's taking dibs? We didn't decide, right?
全然順番決めてなかったね。
Yeah, we haven't.
いいよ。
Fine.
じゃあわため、わためから。こちらから。
All right, let's start with Watame. From here.
私から？
I go first?
あ、大丈夫か。トリ飾りますか。
Uh, you sure you want me last?
あ、お前トリかよ！
Oh wait, you're going last!
喜べよ！
Be glad!
じゃあ、わためから。
Watame, if you please.
私でいい？一番いい？
You sure?
一番バッター、トップバッター！
Leadoff hitter! Top batter!
では。
Okay, then.
お手紙。
Here's my letter.
はい。
Yes.
お手紙読みたいと思います。
I will be reading it now.
やばい、可愛い絵も書いてきてる。
There's a cute drawing in it, too.
おお！
Oh, yeah!
女子じゃん。見せて。
Show it to us!
ありがとう。
Thanks.
ふわふわのやつ書いてきた。
I drew it real fluffy.
め、めくれないよ。あ、よし。
I-I can't open it... Ah, okay.
なんかちょっとドキドキしてきた。
I'm getting all nervous now!
緊張すんだけど。
I'm super nervous!
緊張しないでいいよ。
Don't be!
では読みます。
I'll start.
はい。
Sure.
ココちへ。
To Cocochi,
まさかこんな手紙を書く日が来るとはな。
I never thought I'd need to write a letter like this!
誕生日の時にビデオレターも渡したけど、
I did give you a video message on your birthday,
改めてお手紙を書くね。
but for today, it'll be on paper.
私はデビューが決まった時、
When my debut was decided,
嬉しさ半分、不安半分で、
I was somewhat happy, and somewhat worried
4期生の皆に馴染めるかなとか。
if I could fit in with everyone in 4th Gen,
まともに...あ、噛んじゃった。
or if a noboda—ah, I flubbed.
噛んじゃったね。
Got tongue-tied, huh!
経験がない自分でも活動できるかなとか、
or if a newbie like me would do well at all.
そんな気持ちでいっぱいでした。
That's what I felt.
サムネの作り方も、それを作るために必要なものも知らなくて。
I didn't even know how to make thumbnails for my videos or what I needed to make them.
デビューしてからも緊張しいで、クソ雑魚回線な私は。
And even after debut, I kept freaking out, and had a crappy connection,
そうだったな。
Those were the times!
懐かしいだろ。
How nostawgic...
あんまりポジティブではなかったと思います。
I didn't have much of a positive outlook back then.
そうなの？
Really?
うん。なんかちょっと遅れをとったような。
I felt like I was lagging behind.
そんな気持ちになった時もありました。
That's what I felt like early on.
それら全てを打ち砕いてくれたのが、
The person who managed to break me in despite everything
ココちの存在が大きかったです。
is you, Cocochi.
ココがいたから、今私は挫けずにここにー
Thanks to you, Coco, I can stand here—
ま、座ってるけど、立っていられます。
well, I'm sitting, but—I can stand here without faltering.
そう言っても過言ではありません。
I can say this with full confidence!
何気に朝ココとかでも頼ってくれるのが嬉しかったし、
I'm really happy you let me be on Morning Coco,
相棒って呼んでくれるの、幸せだったよ。
and I'm happy to have been your partner.
ま、これからも私のたった一人の相棒なんですけどね。
You'll be my one-and-only partner, though.
もちろんな。
Of course!
な。
Yeah!
だから卒業しても、いつでも頼ってくれていいし、
Even once you graduate, you can always
何でも力になるから遠慮せず声かけてくれよな。
call on me whenever you feel like you need help!
ありがとう。
Thank you!
あ、それと。
Oh, and also!
ねえ。
Oh?
私が武道館に立つ時には、
When I take the Budokan stage,
ドラゴン用の特別席を用意するので、
I'll be preparing a dragon seat for you,
チケ、チケットを受け取ってくれよな！
complete with a VIP ticket!
おっと！
Really?!
最前列でふんぞり返っていいかい？
Can I be all proud in the front row?
いいよ。
Sure.
でかいからな、でも大丈夫かな。
You'd be pretty large, though?
「私が育てた」ってやっていいかい？
"I raised that girl."
強えドラゴン。
Stwong dragon.
やった。わためより。
Hooray! Love, Watame!
わためありがとう！
Thank you so much, Watame!
お別れですけど、まあわための武道館が、
This may be goodbye,
まだ見てないんで、それまではちょっとな、
but I've yet to see you perform at Budokan,
地球におようかな。
so I'll stick around on Earth until then.
お、いてくれんの？
You'll stick around?
わため頑張れ！頑張るぞ！
Go for it! I'll do my best!
ありがとうよ、わため。
Thanks, Watame.
こちらこそ。
No, thank you.
わためはね、まあ朝ココでね、
Watame was, well...
常にレスが早かったんで、いっぱい使わせていただきました。
She always replied instantly to my requests for help on Morning Coco.
都合のいい女みたいな言い方！
Don't make her sound like she was easy!
都合のいい羊。
My sheepy calls.
めっちゃいい羊だったからな。
You really were a convenient sheep.
でも本当そのおかげでね、色んなコンテンツが作れたんで、助かってたよ。
But it's thanks to you that we made a lot of things happen.
こちらこそ。
Same here.
ありがとう。これからもね。
Thank you to you too. That's why, moving forward...
わため、わためのことは好きだから、卒業してからもね、仲良く。
Watame-Watame- I love ya, Watame, so I hope to be friends even after grad.
何かあったら、ほら、卒業したものにしか分からん
If ya need anything, I—there's some things,
痛みみたいなあるじゃない。
some experiences only alumni would know.
なるほど。
I see!
そういうのいつでも受け付けるから。
AMA.
分かった。
Sure thing!
連絡するわ、すぐ。
I'll call you immediately!
うん、すぐ連絡し。
Yeah, you better!
すぐ連絡しなさいよ。
I will! Yeah, you better!
即レス羊は変わらねえよな。
You'll still be the lightning-fast sheep, right?
そう、すぐ連絡しちゃう。
Yep! I'll call immediately!
ありがとうよ。
Thank you!
こちらこそ。
The pleasure's mine!
ルーナもなんか書いてきてくれたんかい？
What did you write on yours, Luna?
やあ、どうしようみんな。
Gosh, I feel so unprepared!
どうしたルーナ。
What's the matter, Luna?
持ってるじゃん！
But you're holding something!
だって…
Cause I mean, I mean...
みんなお手紙書いてきたって言ってるけど、ルーナお手紙じゃないのー。
Eveyone wrote letters, but I didn't!
え？なになに？なになに？
Say what?!
なになに？
What?!
なに持ってきたんだ？
Then what's that?
これね、ルーナで絵を書いたのらー。
Well, I drew a picture for you!
おー！見たい見たい！
Ooh! Show us!
これをね、ココちゃんにね、見せたいのら。はい。
I'm gonna show it to you, Coco-cha. Here you go!
あー！
Ooh!
可愛い！
It's so cute!
可愛すぎる！
It's too darn cute!
これね... 母の日、母の日の授業参観みたいな... 母の日に貰ったやつだけど、これ。
So this is... She's like a kid showing her mom a school project!
可愛すぎるだろこれ。これね、そう。
This is too cute! So this is...
どうやって説明すればいい？これココちゃん。
Uh-huh. How do I expwain this? This is Coco-cha.
「大好きココちゃん」って書いてあるのらー。
It says, "Wuv you, Coco-cha!"
「大好きココちゃん」って書いてあるのー。
Wuv you, Coco-cha!
可愛い！
That's so sweet!
「大好きココちゃん」って書いたのー。
I wrote, "Wuv you, Coco-cha" on it.
後で額に入れて飾るよ。
And this is... I gotta frame this and hang it up.
あそこのYAGOOの隣あたり...
You can put it next to YAGOO.
あそこに？
Over there?
飾ってくれるのら？
You'll even hang it up?
飾るよ！あのYAGOO、YAGOOいらねえから、YAGOOは。
Of course! We can get rid of that YAGOO and put this there.
本当？
Really?
あそこに飾ってもらっちゃうの？
I get to take his pwace?
ありがとうなのら。
Thank you so much!
ちょっと後で... 後で拡大する。
I've gotta take care of this later.
拡大印刷するしかない。
Gotta enlarge this at a print shop.
拡大？これ説明したいのら。
Enlarge? I wanted to expwain my picture.
説明してほしいのら！
Please do!
立って説明していいのら？
Can I keep standing?
いいよ、いいよ。
Go ahead!
えっとね、これ「大好きココちゃん」ということでね、ココちゃんの絵と、
So, like... It says, "Wuv you, Cococha" here with a picture of you.
あと4期生のみんなの...
And the other Gen 4 members' faces...
顔、顔じゃない...
Wait, not faces.
顔？
Faces?
顔じゃなくて、4期生のみんなのね、チャームポイント的なものをね、
Not their faces, but like, symbols that repwesent each of them.
お一人ずつ書きました。
可愛いのらー。ありがとうなのら。
It's so cute! Thank you so much, Luna!
これココちゃんに差し上げます。
So this... This is for you, Cococha.
ありがとう！受け取ってください。ありがとう！
Thank you so much! Please take it. Thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
よかったー！可愛いー！
So sweet! So sweet!
ルーナは、ココとの思い出なんかある？
So, got any special memories with Coco?
ココちゃんとの思い出ね、一番はね、
Well, what I wemember most...
うん。
Uh-huh.
あれなのら。ホラーゲーム。
...is the time we played a horror game together.
あー！やってたね！
I remember that!
一番最初にココちゃんとやったの。
It was the first thing we did together.
やってたね。
It sure was!
座ろう座ろう。
I'm gonna sit down.
またね、一緒にずっと遊べると思ってたからね。
I thought we'd always have more chances to play together.
うんうん。
Uh-huh.
ココちゃんと何かやりたいと思ったら、
'Cause wike, I wanted to do something with you.
ココちゃんって一番最初ホラーゲームばっかやってたのらよ。
And early on, you mostly pwayed horror games.
あー確かにな。
That's right, I did!
ホラーゲームのイメージしかなかったのらよ。
I thought horror games were your thing,
だからココちゃんとやるときはホラーゲームかなと思って。
so if we pwayed together, that's what we should do.
頑張ってくれたんか、それで。
So you grit your teeth and did it?
一生懸命頑張ったけど、やっぱり怖すぎたからもう辞めちまったのら。
Yeah, I twied my best, but they were too scawy, so I quit.
辞めちまったんか！
You quit?!
あはははは！
Hahahaha!
辞めちまったけど、それでもね、
I quit doing horror,
ココちゃんとできた、すごいいい思い出だったのら。
but getting to pway with you was a really nice memory.
うれしいのら。怖かったけどね。
I'm so happy to hear that! The games were scawy, though!
また一緒にって言えないのが悲しいけど。
I wish I could say, "Let's pway again sometime."
でもルーナとは、もうちょっといっぱい遊びたかったよ。二人きりで。
Even so... I wish we could have hung out more, just the two of us.
あー！だめなのらー！
Nooo! This sucks!
卒業しても遊ぶんだ、遊ぶんだ。
We can still hang out, even after you graduate!
遊ぶのら！
Absolutely!
みんなも？
With you guys, too?
All of us!
みんなも！みんなで遊ぶのら！
We can all have fun together!
一緒に行く！遊ぼうや！
We can hang out!
遊びに来てください、かなココハウスに。
Drop by KanaCoco House anytime!
かなココハウスに！いつでも来いよ。
To KanaCoco House!
行く行く！
Sure! Of course!
タコパしてくれる？
Can we have a takoyaki party?
タコパしようや！
Yeah, let's do it!
タコパしようぜ！
任せろ任せろ、ここは。得意だから。
Leave it to me. I'll do this part. She's good at it.
本当？じゃあルーナタコさん切るから。
She is? Then I'll chop up the octopus!
お！切れるの？ルーナが動き出す！
Really? Luna's taking charge!
ルーナが自分でやるのか？やるのら！
Luna, you're actually gonna do something yourself? I'll do it!
頼むぞ、楽しみー！
We're counting on you! Can't wait!
では次は、トワ。トワ様も何か書いてきてくれたんかい？
Now, next is Towa! Did you write something for me, too?
まあな。書きました。
Well yeah... I did!
ありがとう... ありがとう。
Thank you... thank you.
トワね、うまく言葉にするのが苦手というか。やっぱり語彙力が...
You know, I'm really not good at putting stuff into words.
薄い悪魔なんで。精一杯書かせていただきました。
I'm a devil with a weak vocabulary. I wrote what I could.
ルーナほどじゃないのら。大丈夫。
Don't wowwy, it's not as weak as mine.
え？！結構相当ひどいよ。
What?! It's quite really bad.
相当、相当ひどい！
Quite really! Quite really bad.
じゃあ読ませていただきます。行け！
Okay, I'm going to read it now. Go ahead.
ココへ。
Dear Coco,
手紙を書くのは久しぶりです。
It's been a while since I've written a letter.
しかもね、渡す相手の目の前で読むのも初めてです。
And what's more, it's the first time I've ever read one
渡す相手の目の前で読むのも初めてです。
to the person it's addressed to.
少し恥ずかしいけど読みます。
It's a bit embarrassing, but here I go.
まずココのことを第一に尊敬しています。
To start with, I look up to you, Coco.
えっ？！
What?!
いつもしポジティブなところとか、
Your relentless positivity,
優しいところ、
your kindness,
言葉のチョイスが面白いところといっぱいあります。
your amusing word choice, and much more.
デビューしてホロライブを盛り上げたいと言っていて、
When you debuted, you said you wanted more excitement in hololive,
それを実現させる力が本当にすごいなと思っていました。
and I thought your ability to actually make that happen was amazing.
4期生それぞれデビューしてから、いろいろ悩んでいたところを、
After the rest of the 4th Gen debuted, we encountered various problems,
ココがエンターテインメントとしてキャラクターを作ってくれたね。
and you turned them into entertainment and made them part of our identities.
すごく助けられました。
That was a big help to us.
ダンス練習も楽しかった。
Dance practice was fun, too.
ご飯も行ったり、タコパしたり、思い出がたくさんあります。
I have a lot of memories of us going out to eat, having takoyaki parties, and stuff like that.
ココの伝説は、ココが卒業しても
Your legend will continue to live on,
ずっと残っているし、
even after you graduate,
みんなの記憶に残っていることだと思います。
and I believe that nobody will forget you.
ココの卒業の話を聞いた時、
When I heard that you were graduating,
驚きすぎて言葉が出てこなかったです。
I was shocked speechless.
考えれば考えるほどやっぱり泣けたし、
The more that I thought about it, the more I cried,
想像ができなかったかなって。
and I couldn't imagine it happening.
しかもそして、今でもできてないちょっと。本当に。
Honestly, even now, I still can't, really.
おい…わかる？本当に明日からいないの？
Hey... Are you really not gonna be around from tomorrow?
いないな…そうかもね。
Yeah... Seems so.
泣きそう…
I'm gonna cry...
でも、ずっとくよくよしてたり元気なかったら、
But... if I mope about it and be all sad,
ココは何しとんねんみたいな感じで怒ってくると思うし。
I know you'll just get mad like, "the hell you doin'!"
うんうんうん。
Yup.
4期生が4人という形になっても、
The 4th Generation may look like it has four members from now on,
いつまでも4期生は5人で、
but there will always be five of us,
4期生としてトワは頑張っていこうと思います。
and I will continue to work hard as one of them.
大好きなココ、
I love you so much, Coco,
ホロライブを卒業しても遊ぼうね。
and I hope we can hang out after you graduate too.
ココの新しい道が明るくて
I hope that the path along your new journey
幸せがたくさん満ちたものとなりますように。
is sparkling with happiness and joy.
いつまでもずっとずっと願っております。
And I wish it stays that way forever and ever.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
常闇トワより。
From Tokoyami Towa.
泣くなー！
Don't cry!
すごいいろいろ考えたら泣けちゃって…
I just started thinking about a bunch of stuff...
思いがあふれちゃったんだね。まったく！
It overwhelmed you.
本当に！
Really!
手紙をどうぞ。はい。
Please have this letter.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ボロボロだね。
It's a bit messy.
ごめん。
Sorry.
笑顔で最後までいたかったんだけど…
I wanted to keep smiling until the end...
まったくトワ様最初から最後まで泣き虫だぜ。
Since the very start, you always have and still do cry easily, Towa-sama.
本当だね。
Yeah.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you for everything.
トワ様…
Towa-sama...
本当に、ね、私の卒業は突然だったから。
Really, y'know, my graduation was sudden.
突然だったので。
It was so sudden.
一番びーびー泣いてたのは多分トワ様…
I think the one who bawled the most was Towa-sama.
そうだね。
But, you know,
あ、ほら、スイッチがさ、ココの元に入り、
we finally got a Switch in Coco's hands.
そのスイッチで最後みんなでマリオカートとかできて、
And with it, we all got to play Mario Kart together in the end.
それもすごくもうそれも思い出になってる。
That also became a great memory.
なってるね。
It did.
Yeah.
ちゃんと思い出は作れたから悔いはないかな。
Since we were able to make those memories, I suppose I have no regrets.
悔いって言っちゃうと、もっと遊びたかったからそれはたくさんある。
Well, saying that, I really wanted to play with you guys more. So maybe I have a bunch of them!
うん。
Yeah.
それは考えないようにしよう。
But let's not think about that.
はい。
Okay.
トワ様ありがとう。
Towa-sama, thank you.
ありがとう、ココち！
Thank you, Cocochi!
お手紙大事にするよ。
I'll treasure your letter.
うん。
Okay!
ま、卒業した後も遊ぼうや！
Well, let's all have more fun together after I graduate!
遊ぼう！
Yeah!
遊ぶ遊ぶ！
I'll still be here!
地球にはもうちょっといようかな。
I guess I'll hang around on Earth for a while longer.
よろしく。
I look forward to it.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
うん。
Yeah.
さて、お前。かなたか。お前、お前！
Now you, Kanata. You. You!
初めてこんな手紙なんかココに書いてきましたよ。
This is the first time I've written a letter to you, Coco.
おお！
Yeah!
ちょっと、いっぱい書いたんですけど、
Okay. I wrote a lot,
読ませていただきたいと思います！
so I'm going to read it now!
うん。
Okay.
ココへ。
Dear Coco,
とうとうこの日が来ました。
The day has finally come.
すごく寂しいです。
It's a very sad feeling.
ココと出会って同期として、仲間として、
I've spent a year and a half with you as my genmate, as my colleague,
友達として、家族として過ごして
my friend, my friend...
1年半だったね。
and my family.
最初ココがもうスピードで僕たちの前を走っていった時、
In the beginning, when you blew past the rest of us at super speed,
その背中に憧れたし尊敬しました。
I really admired you and wanted to be like you.
本当に一人で圧倒的で、
You were in a league of your own,
同期として並ぶのが怖いとか萎縮しそうにもなりました。
and I didn't know if I deserved to stand on equal footing with you.
でもそんな才能にあふれたココが孤独にならないように、
But I remember thinking that I had to work my tail off
僕が同期が隣に立てるように必死で頑張らないといけないって
to be able to stand by that super-talented woman's side
思ったのを覚えています。
so I could make sure that she wouldn't be all alone.
最初は本当に僕は実力不足で、
When I started, my skills were lacking,
ココのオマケとか、ココにおんぶに抱っことか言われまくったりしたし、
and people were saying I was "Coco's sidekick" or "just leeching off Coco,"
実際その通りだと思っていました。
and I really believed that.
今はちゃんと隣に立てていると嬉しいです。
But if I'm able to stand by your side on my own merit now, that would make me really happy.
ココと一緒にいるのは本当に楽で、
Being with you is so comforting,
もう何年も一緒にいるような長年連れ添った夫婦のような感じがします。
it feels like we're an old married couple who've been together forever.
ココは僕の前ではうるさくて適当でがさつで下品でゲップもするけど、
When we're together, you're noisy, sloppy, crude, and you even burp!
たつのこの前ではたくさん僕の話をしてくれていて、
But I was always happy when you would talk so much about me
いつも嬉しかったよ。
in front of your fans.
実はめちゃめちゃチェックしてました！
To be honest, I watched you a lot!
あんなふうに僕の話をしてくれることがなくなると思うと、すごくすごく寂しいです。
When I think about how you won't be talking about me like that anymore, it makes me really sad.
デビューしてから先輩を追い抜く勢いで盛り上げると突っ走る姿、
Since your debut, I've seen your drive to not be outdone by our predecessors.
ホロライブのみんなが大事になって守りたいものが増えて、
I've seen the kindness you showed everyone when hololive became really important to you
...て、みんなに優しさをくれた姿。
...and for showing kindness to everyone.
辛いことがあったとき、強がって平気のふりをしていたけど
I've seen you putting on a brave face and pretending everything was fine during the hard times,
本当は一人で悩んでいた姿
when in reality you were worrying about it alone.
ホロライブに活気をくれた姿、全部忘れないよ。
I've seen you bring prosperity to hololive. And I'll never forget any of that!
本当に、本当によく頑張ったね。
You did a really, really great job!
誰よりも大好きだ。かなココは永遠だもんな。
I love you more than anyone! KanaCoco is forever!
これからもよろしくね。今夜はハーゲンを奢ってくれよな。
Let's keep it going! And you're treating me to some Häagen tonight, right?
お前が奢れよ！
You treat me!
ということで、僕もね、実は急いで書きました。
Oh, man... Okay, done. I had to write all that in a rush, too.
ちょっとね、こんな...
And, like... It looks pretty bad...
ちょっと... ちょっと...
Let me... Let me...
きったねえな。あ、ごめん、そこでいいの？あの
Damn, that's packed. Let me take this chance now.
ホロライブのみんなにちょっと呼びかけをしまして、僕、ちょっと寄せ書きをみんなに書いてもらいました。
Hmm? I reached out to the other hololive members, and got them to write messages for you.
マジで？！
What?!
なのでちょっとちゃんと、ちゃんとしたものもね、出したいと思います。本当に。
And now I'll hand the whole thing over.
あー！本当にもう、みんなからだ。ありがとう。
Ahh! Seriously... It's seriously from all of hololive. Thank you so much for everything.
ココちゃーん！
Coco-chan!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you all!
嬉しい泣きなの、うう...
These are tears of joy.
本当にありがとう、ありがとう。
Thank you!
手紙渡すの忘れた。
Oh, I forgot to hand you my letter!
みんな大好きだ！
Love you all!
みんなあの、えー、泣かすんじゃないよ！
So, uh... Don't make me cry, dammit!
誰が泣かせたのは？せっかく盛り上げたのにみんな泣かせたのは！
Who made it wain in here after I livened things up?!
我慢してたのに！
I thought I was all out of tears!
あのー、まあ、４期生のみんなとはね、あの、申し訳ないことをしたね。でも。
Well, um... I feel bad for putting you guys through this.
何がだよ！
What do you mean?
えーもう、やだー
Huh? I mean, uh...
いや、卒業をね、まあ、そういうことになったっていうことだ。だね。
The fact that I'm graduating.
そんなことないよ！
Don't feel bad.
うんうん。
Yeah, don't.
ずっと５人だから。
We'll always be five in spirit.
すごい、たぶんいっぱいっぱい、すごい長い間考えて決めたことだと思うから、
I know you spent a lot of time mulling over the decision.
私たちはそれをいけないことだと思ってないし、
All of us think you're entitled to that decision,
ココが新しい道を進むっていうのも、私たちはすごい応援をする。し、
and we'll cheer you on in whatever you do next.
本当に、さっきも言ったけど、私たちが５人で４期生っていうことは絶対変わらないから、
Also, like I said, the fact that there's five of us won't ever change.
うん、寂しいけど。
We'll miss you, though.
そう、なんかイベントがあったときとかは、ドラゴン席があるし。
We'll leave a dragon-sized seat open whenever there's an event and stuff.
ドラゴン席！
Dragon-sized!
そうだよ、ドラゴン席！用意してくれるかい？
That's right! Dragon-sized! Will you really?
用意してるでしょ！
Of course we will!
あー。じゃあちょっと最前列でお拝見させてくれよな。
Cool! Then you'll see me looking all proud in the front row.
最っ強の御出組み足組ませてもらうわ。
The proudest of onlookers.
やってくれよな。
Do it, seriously.
みんな、ホロライブに残って、あ、残りじゃねえや、ホロライブに残って、
I believe you guys will keep... Wait, correction. I believe you guys will keep...
どこまでもね輝いていけると思っています。
...shining bright here in hololive.
私はね、ホロライブからは居なくなっちゃいますけど、
As for me, I'll be leaving hololive,
まあ私はね、たぶん、あの、どこ行っても輝いちゃうんで。ね！
but I know I'll shine bright wherever I go. Right!
かっけーな！
Damn, you cool!
どこ行っても輝いちゃうから！
I'll shine no matter where I go!
辛くなったらいつでも戻って来いよ。
Feel free to come back if things go south.
おう、そうだね。
Yeah.
まあ、YAGOOが死んだ頃に戻って来るわ。YAGOOが死んだら連絡しような。
Well, YAGOO will probably be dead by then. Get in touch once he is.
YAGOOが死んだら連絡くれよ、私がYAGOOの席に。
Let me know when he passes. Let me know when he passes.
死ななくても連絡しようよ！
Can we keep in touch even otherwise?!
本当だよ！普通だよ！
We should, huh? Truly.
まあね、また会えるさ。
Well, we'll see each other again.
え、また会えるさ！
We'll see each other again!
会えるさ！会えるよ！
Yeah, we can! We will!
誰よりも幸せでいてくれ。
Please be happy. You deserve it more than anyone.
幸せだよ！
I already am!
ありがとう、わため！
Thanks... Watame!
よしよし。ほら笑顔でお別れだぞ。
There, there. Let's say our goodbyes with a smile.
ね、この後はライブもあるから。
We've got a show to put on.
そうそう、こっからこっから。
We're just getting started!
あの、あ！鼻水拭いてください。
So... Ack! Wipe your nose!
鼻水拭きます。
Wipe your nose.
顔ぐちゃぐちゃなのな。
Doing just that!
えーっと、みんなにね、視聴者の皆さんずっと応援してくれたファンの皆さん、
Um, well, to all my viewers, all my fans who've supported me,
４期生をね、大好きでずっと応援してくれていたファンの皆さんもね、
and 4th Gen fans who have loved and supported us...
たくさんいると思うから。
I'm sure there's a bunch of you.
そっか、たわね、最後にね...
You guys make sure you don't...
わためみたいにこんなんなんないように！
...end up like Watame here.
そうね。
Yeah.
しょぼしょぼ顔になんないようにね。
Don't start ugly crying.
あの、派手に送り出してほしい！
I want you all to send me off with a bang.
送り出すぞ！
We'll do just that!
盛り上げていくぞ！
Let's get hyped!
私のいないホロライブを頼んだぞ！
Take care of hololive after I'm gone.
任せろ！
You got it!
任せて！
We'll take good care of it!
大丈夫かな？私がいなくてホロライブ...
Is hololive gonna be okay without me?
任せなさいよ！大丈夫！
Don't worry about it!
みんながいるから大丈夫だよな？
It'll be fine with you guys, right?
大丈夫だ！
Totally!
任せろ！
Absolutely!
元気で！元気で！元気で！
Be well! Live strong!
お前らもな、幸せに...
You guys... be happy...
バカッ！
Gah!
ありがとう、今日来てくれて。
Thank you all for coming today.
ありがとう。こちらこそ。
Thank you. No, thank you.
手紙も一生大事にするぜ！
I'll treasure these letters forever!
飾ってね！絶対飾ってね！
Good wuck! Be the best!
頑張ります！ありがとう！
I'll do my best! Thank you!
ここからは見せるぜ！
Be ready to lose your shit.
それじゃ、卒業ライブ本番、行くか！
Alright then, let's go to the graduation live performance!
イエーイ！
Let's get hyped!
Shiny Smily Story
それぞれ違った
In each of our different
心で
hearts
走れ GO!
Run, GO!
どこ見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
No matter where I looked, it was pitch black, but then it sprouted...
ほんの小さな希望に
A tiny bit of hope
この瞳奪われた
stole my gaze
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Expertly tuning my heart that wavered with anxiety
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I was squeezing out just a tiny bit of courage
諦めの文字デリートして進む
I'll delete the word 'give up' and move forward
苦しい時ももう私は
Even in painful times, I'm no longer...
一人じゃないから
...alone anymore
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams even more
ワクワク止まらない
This excitement won't stop
想像を超えていく
Exceeding imagination
世界見せてあげる
I'll show you the world
アクセスしてみたい
I want to try to access it
後悔なんてそうさせない
I won't let you have any regrets
それぞれ違った
In each of our different
心で
hearts
走れ GO!
Run, GO!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
These radiant feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光もリアルに届けるよ
Will deliver even unseen lights into reality
いつも聴こえるエールはここにキャプチャして
Capturing the yells I always hear right here
もっと新しい光を探したくなるよ
It makes me want to search for an even newer light
君の笑顔は保存して進む
I'll save your smile and move forward
悲しい時に見返すよ
I'll look back at it in sad times
力が湧くから
Because it gives me strength
胸を張って夢追いかけたい
With head held high, I want to chase my dreams
奇跡のストーリー
A story of miracles
一緒に作ろう
Let's build it together
終わらない夢を
A never-ending dream
誰一人欠かせない
Not a single person can be missed
愛が舞ったこの世界
In this world where love has danced
それぞれ違った
In each of our different
心で
hearts
彩れ！
Color it!
悲しい時も
Even in sad times
寂しい時も
Even in lonely times
信じ合えるのがある
There is something we can believe in together
忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
Without forgetting, I want to keep this heartbeat sounding out
終わらない世界に溢れ出すよ笑顔たち
Smiles will overflow into this never-ending world
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on that stage I've longed for
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine in my own way
時に涙して
Sometimes shedding tears
また笑い合いたい
I want to laugh with you again
おんなじ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
踏み出そう奇跡の一歩
Let's take a miraculous step forward
息切らして夢追いかけたい
I want to chase my dreams until I'm out of breath
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement doesn't stop
想像を超えていく
Going beyond imagination
世界見せてあげる
I'll show you the world
アクセスしてみない？
Why not try to access it?
後悔なんてここにない
There are no regrets here
それぞれ違った
With our each unique hearts,
心でつくるわ
we'll create it
へっ！
Heh!
みんな！
Everyone!
アイドル衣装で、
In our idol costumes,
初めて
for the first time...
一緒のステージに立てたのになあ！
...we were able to stand on the same stage together!
初めて言ったな...
It's our first time...
どれどれどれ？
Let's see, let's see.
見せてみな。
Show us.
見せて見せて。
Show us, show us.
なるほど、なるほどな。
I see, I see.
せーの！
Ready, go!
うぶっ！
Oof!
かわいい！
So cute!
かわいいのな！
It's cute!
It's so cute!
かわいいのな！
So cute!
うーん...
Hmm...
ぺったんこやんけ！
You're so flat!
誰がぺったんこやん！
Who are you calling flat?!
あの...
Um...
ちょっと後ろのイラストが気になるんですけど、
I'm a bit curious about the illustration behind us.
これ、ちょっと一体どなた...？
Who on earth is this...?
あ、これ！
Oh, this!
YAMAママ、パパんからの、え、卒業プレゼント！
It's a graduation present from Yama-mama and Papa!
うわあ！すごい！
Wow! Amazing!
めっちゃかわいい！
It's so cute!
4期生も舞台になってるよ！
Even the 4th gen is on stage!
誰がパネルマジックだ馬鹿野郎。
Who's a 'panel magic' idiot? You jerk.
だまれよこれちょっと。
Just stop it.
馬鹿にしすぎだよ君！
You're making too much fun of me!
誰？
Who is it?
ほらほらほら、君写真と違うね？
Hey, hey, you look different from your photo, right?
別人じゃねえの？
Aren't you a different person?
君違う人だよこれ。
You're a different person.
目を見つめる顔よ。
Look at that staring face.
いやでもほんとなんか旅立ちって感じで
But really, it feels like a departure...
すごく...なんか力強くもあって。
...it feels very powerful too.
ママ、パパありがとう！
Mama, Papa, thank you!
美しい！
Beautiful!
すごい！
Amazing!
ママ、パパありがとう！
Mama, Papa, thank you!
ルーナもいる！
Luna is here too!
みんないる！
Everyone is here!
ね、4期生全部...なんか
Wait, all of Gen 4... and there's also...
なんか、なんかいるよ他にも。
...something else too.
あれ？後ろになんかいない？
Is there something behind?
あれ？
Oh?
なんか化け物とあと...
Some monsters and...
化け物いるな！
There are monsters!
あれ？なんかいない？
Wait? Is that something?
あ、なんかタツノコいるもしかして？
Oh? Is that a Tatsunoko?
一緒に来るの？お前らも。
Are you guys coming too?
お前タツノコ？
Are you a Tatsunoko?
あ、一緒に来るのか。
Ah, so you're coming with me.
一緒に来るか！
You're coming with me!
旅立ちだね。
It's a departure.
新しく旅をしてくるよ、みんな。私は。
I'm going on a new journey, everyone.
嫌なのら...ルーナは嫌なのら...
I don't want to... Luna doesn't want to...
寂しい...
I'm lonely...
So lonely...
待てよまだ...
Wait, we still...
まだみんなで一緒に歌える曲があるだろ？
We still have a song we can all sing together, right?
あ、そっか。
Oh, that's right.
あるだろ。あるよね。
We do. We still have one.
せっかくアイドル衣装でこんなにかわいくなったんだから...
We're all dressed up in these cute idol costumes...
おそろ、おそろ、おそろ。
...matching, matching, matching.
アイ・シャル・アイ・チー！
I shall I chi!
オソロッチ！オソロッチだ！
Matching! We're matching!
せっかくタイのね、
Since we're together...
タイを持つものはね、やっぱりね...
...those who have 'tai' (waki), as you'd expect...
タイを持つ...
Those with 'tai'...
匂いかいどけ、匂いかいどけ。
Take a sniff, take a sniff.
うぶっ、酸っぱい！酸っぱい！
Ugh, sour! It's sour!
ルーナも酸っぱいのら！お前！馬鹿！
You're sour too, Luna! You idiot!
うぶっ、酸っぱい！
Ugh, sour!
ルーナも酸っぱいって...
Luna's sour too...
かなたんが酸っぱいって言うんや！お前か！
Kanata-tan said it's sour! Was it you?!
ルーナ...ルーナ、
Luna... Luna...
私卒業するのら。
...I'm graduating.
嫌なのら。ずっとここにいるのら。
I don't want to. Stay here forever.
ちょっとね、一人だけまだ信じられてない、卒業することを。
One person still can't believe I'm graduating.
じゃあここにいるわ。
Then I'll stay here.
あ、あ、私もじゃあここにいるわ。
Then I'll stay here too.
あるめので、ルーナもここにいようぜ。
Let's stay here together, Luna.
あ、かなたもここにいようぜ。
Ah, let's stay here too, Kanata.
もう一生ここにいるか。
Shall we just stay here forever?
じゃあ私もここにいるわ。
Then I'll stay here too.
うふふ、うふふ。
Ehehe, ehehe.
ね、あの...もっとみんなで、
Hey... I want to keep...
ね、こんなアイドル衣装でかわいく歌いたいけど、
...singing cute songs with everyone in these idol costumes,
もう時間がね...そうだね...
but we're running out... of time...
なくなってきちゃったから、かなた。
...we're running out of time, Kanata.
ね、みんなで、こうして歌うのは5人で。
This will be the last time we sing together as five.
次の曲で本当の本当の本当に最後になりますわ。
The next song will truly, truly, truly be the last.
うん、次の曲はね、え、僕が本当に、
Yeah, the next song is one that I actually...
あの、作らせていただきましてみんなに本当に歌っていただいた曲がありまして、
...wrote and had everyone sing.
「キセキ結び」という曲なんですけど。
It's called 'Kiseki Musubi' (Milky Way).
ありがとうだよ。
Thank you.
ちょっとさっき泣いちゃったから、もう...
I cried a bit earlier, so...
もう泣かないでね。
...please don't cry anymore.
ちょっと！泣いちゃったよね。
Hey! You did cry.
もう泣かないで。
Don't cry anymore.
やばいここで。
Oh man, right here.
ありがとうよ。
Thank you.
どろっどろだったけど
It was a complete mess but
明るく
brightly,
うん
yeah.
最後は明るくね
Let's end on a bright note.
うん
Yeah.
一緒に
Together.
笑顔で
With a smile.
笑顔でね
みんなと一緒にね
With everyone together.
だから
So,
みんなも一緒に歌ってください
please everyone sing along too.
それでは
And now,
キセキ結び
Kiseki Musubi.
キセキ結び / 作詞・作曲：天音かなた 編曲：ハム
Kiseki Musubi / Lyrics & Music: Amane Kanata Arrangement: Hamu
約束しよう 僕ら出会えた奇跡
Let's make a promise, the miracle that brought us together
忘れないように
So we never forget it
夢描いて集う
Gathering to draw our dreams,
最終アニメみたいな
like the final episode of an anime,
ハッピーなエンドになる彼方へ飛ぶよ
we'll fly towards a happy ending in the distance.
眠気あくびして
Yawning from sleepiness,
今日は何をしようか
what shall we do today?
常世に続く海を駆け抜ける
Running through the sea that stretches for eternity.
今は溜息よりも勇気を
For now, have courage rather than sighs.
諦めるなんてないの ここで歌う
There's no giving up, we'll sing right here.
僕の声は聞こえてますか
Can you hear my voice?
君に届け
May it reach you.
学校の友達じゃ きっと出会い得なかった
If we were school friends, we never would have met.
画面の先の遥か遠くまで
To the far reaches beyond the screen,
笹くれた言葉も 誰かの笑顔になる
even splintered words will bring a smile to someone.
それぞれの色で 星結ぶ奇跡
Tracing the stars with our own colors,
キラキラ輝くステージに 連れて行くよ
I'll take you to the sparkling stage.
泣いて笑って燥いで 毎日ジェットコースター
Crying, laughing, having fun, every day is a roller coaster.
たまには寝転んでお昼寝しよう
Let's lie down and nap once in a while.
ちょっと自信ない時 琴りとデュエットして
When you lack confidence, duet with a bird.
今日だけは泣いちゃうこと 許してね
Please forgive me for crying just for today.
未来の僕がアルバム開く
My future self will open the album.
傷ついた写真だって 宝物だ
Even the photos of being hurt are treasures.
僕の愛が見えていますか
Can you see my love?
君に届け
May it reach you.
格好も個性も 性格も違うけれど
Our looks, individuality, and personalities are different, but
弱気な時は瞼 ぎゅっと瞑り
when feeling weak, close your eyes tight.
もう一回 もう一回 絶対に諦めない
One more time, one more time, I'll never give up.
前の背中追う 下手っぴな僕でも
Even if I'm unskillful, following the back in front of me,
君の隣に行きたくて 走るの
I run because I want to be by your side.
誰にも言えずに描いた夢が たとえ叶わないとしても
Even if the dream I drew in secret doesn't come true,
ボロボロの靴でも 格好良くなくても
even with worn-out shoes, even if I'm not cool,
幼いあの日の僕なら何て言う？ 止まらないで
what would my younger self say? "Don't stop."
初めて僕ら出会った日 まるで
The day we first met feels just like
昨日のように 思い出すけど
yesterday, when I look back on it.
ああ行こうか
Ah, shall we go?
最後に今 重なる五人の奇跡
Finally now, the miracle of the five overlapping.
僕の声は聞こえてますか
Can you hear my voice?
君に届け
May it reach you.
黒板のメッセージ 桜の風抜けて
The message on the blackboard, passing through the cherry blossom wind,
僕らの声を聞いて ずっとずっと
listen to our voices, forever and ever.
嬉しい日 楽しい日 哀しい日 別れの日も
Happy days, fun days, sad days, even the day of parting,
それぞれの色で 星結ぶ奇跡
tracing the stars with our own colors.
キラキラ輝くステージで 約束しよう
Let's make a promise on the sparkling stage.
いつかここで また会おう
Let's meet here again someday.
終わったー！
It's over!
やりきったー！
We did it!
言葉がなくなってしまいました
I've run out of words.
本当に
Truly.
歌って
Singing...
トワ、元気か？
Towa, you okay?
元気！
Energetic!
元気だよ本当に最後
I'm really energetic at the very end.
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
最高！本当に最高！
The best! That was really the best!
愛されてるわ。
You're so loved.
愛してるよ！
I love you!
みんな愛してるよ！
I love you all!
いや、やっぱ4期生の、この曲...
Man, this 4th gen song...
かなたんがね...
Kanatan made it...
寝坊がきっかけですけど。
...and it all started with her oversleeping.
自腹でね、作らせていただいて。
She paid for it out of her own pocket.
本当にみんなに歌ってもらえて、
I'm so glad everyone could sing it,
最高の曲なのに。
even though it's such a great song.
神曲！神曲！神曲！
It's a god-tier song! A god-tier song!
本当にね、この卒業ライブの日に間に合うように、
Honestly, I wanted it to be ready for this graduation live,
この時歌えるようにと思ってね、作って...
so that we could sing it at this very moment...
もうこれで最後でもいいと思って作ったんで...
I made it thinking it could even be the last thing I do...
あ、
Ah,
あの、ちょっと言いたいことあるんですけど。
Wait, I actually have something I want to say.
なんかね、かなたんが配信とかでも
You've said in streams and such
「これで最後でもいい」って言ってましたけど、
that "it's okay if this is the last time,"
この曲できればね、
but if possible,
4期生みんなでね、また歌ってほしい...
I want all the 4th gen members to sing it again...
私がいなくてもね、歌ってほしい...
even when I'm gone...
と思ってんだよね！
...that's what I'm thinking!
歌うしかないな、これはな！
Then we have no choice but to sing it!
そう、みんなで歌って。
Yeah, everyone should sing it.
まあちょっとね、4人...パートが分かれてるから、
Well, since there are four of you... the parts are split up,
私のパート、名前も入ってるしな、歌詞に。
and my part even has my name in the lyrics.
まあでも、せっかく作った、
But still, it's the song that was made with such care,
私の大好きな曲なんで。
and it's a song I love so much.
みんなが残り4人になっても歌ってるのを、私は聞きたいよ！
I want to hear you four continue to sing it!
歌おう！
Let's sing it!
ココが言うなら、私達、意志継いで...
If Coco says so, then we'll carry on her will...
歌っていこう！歌っていこう！
...and keep singing it! Let's do it!
ありがとう。元気出そうよ。
Thank you. Let's cheer up.
元気出そう、歌う、歌う。
Let's cheer up and sing, let's sing.
あ、せっかく...これちょっと、
Ah, while we're here... wait,
あれ？この並び...
hold on. This line-up...
なんか懐かしいね、この並び。
This line-up feels really nostalgic.
なんか懐かしくない？この並び。
Doesn't this line-up feel nostalgic?
あ、ちょっとTwitterのヘッダーにしてる画像が...！
Ah, wait! It's that image I use for my Twitter header!
前に撮った写真がありましたよね。
There was a photo we took a while back.
ちょっとこれ、再現できんじゃない？
Can't we recreate that right now?
再現しちゃってみる？
Should we try to recreate it?
私達の顔を横に並べると、
It's the photo where if you line up our faces,
身長差で実はこうなっているっていう写真です。
you can see how our heights actually compare.
懐かしいなー！
This is so nostalgic!
あ、こんなんだったわ！懐かしい。
Ah, it was just like this! So nostalgic.
デビュー当時、これで写真撮って、
Back when we debuted, we took a photo like this,
私、辛かったんだよな。
and it was so hard for me.
プルプル...プルプル...足が...足が...
Shaking... shaking... my legs... my legs...
あ、これやりたかったんだよ、最後に。
Ah, I really wanted to do this one last time.
あー！ルナが！ルナが死んでる！
Ah! Luna! Luna's dying!
ダメージが！ルナ様ダメだよ！
The damage! Luna-sama, don't give in!
これ、膝曲げてバランスとるの意外と大変なんだよな。
It's actually really hard to keep your balance with your knees bent like this.
結構大変だわ。
It's quite tough.
いやー、これやりたかったわ。忘れるとこだった。
Man, I really wanted to do that. I almost forgot.
やれてよかった、本当にね。
I'm glad we could do it, truly.
え、ちょっと待って、一つ思い出したんだけどさ、
Wait a minute, I just remembered something.
私達さ、3Dになったらプロレスするって言ってなかったっけ？
Didn't we say that we'd do pro-wrestling once we got our 3D models?
プロレス！プロレス！言ってたわ！
Pro-wrestling! Pro-wrestling! We did say that!
4期生全員でやるか？
Shall all of us 4th gen members do it now?
やったるかー！やったるかー！
Let's do it! Let's do it!
ルナとは戦えないのだわ。
I can't fight with Luna-tan.
姫様なのに甘いのだわ。姫様なのに！
She's too sweet for a princess. Even though she's a princess!
よーし、おらおらおら！
Alright, take this! Ora ora ora!
お前！
You!
4期生は強い！4期生は強い！
4th gen is strong! 4th gen is strong!
ひり、にり...踏み潰されちゃう...
I'm... I'm gonna get crushed...
落穂拾いだわ！
That was like picking up scraps!
勝ったな。弱々しいな。
I won. You're so weak.
まだまだ出直してきなさい。
You need to go back and train some more.
ではね、そろそろ、みんな。
Well then, it's about time, everyone.
私のアイドルとしての...
My last performance...
最後のステージを見せたい！
...as an idol, I want to show it to you!
ここって、アイドルだよね？
We're idols here, aren't we?
それはわからんけど...
I'm not so sure about that...
それはずっとできなかったけど...
We were never really able to be that...
アイドル、最後ぐらいは！
At least at the very end!
最後ぐらいは、アイドルとして終わらせてくれ！
At least let me end this as an idol!
ずっとアイドルでいてほしい！
I want you to be an idol forever!
アイドルっぽいのやってよ！
Do something idol-like!
それじゃあ、新感覚アイドルなんだよな。
Well then, I'm a new type of idol.
というわけでね、最後に、
And so, finally,
私のオリジナルソング、
my original song,
桐生ココオリジナルソングをね、
Kiryu Coco's original song...
みんなに聞いてほしいです！
I want everyone to hear it!
聞きたい！
We want to hear it!
ま、移動しようぜ！ここじゃあな...
Well, let's move! This isn't the place...
そうだね、いつもの、見慣れた、
Right, to our usual, familiar...
私たちのステージに来いよ！
...stage! Come on!
遅いよ、みんな！
You're too slow, everyone!
足早いの？
Are you fast on your feet?
はい！ピッピッピッ！ホイホイホイホイ！
Yes! Pi-pi-pi! Hoi hoi hoi hoi!
あ、疲れ連れて来ないよね？
Ah, you didn't bring any fatigue, right?
はい！ピッピッピッ！ホイホイホイホイ！
Yes! Pi-pi-pi! Hoi hoi hoi hoi!
せーの、ピッピッ！ピッピッピッピッ！へー！ピッピッピッ！
Ready, set, pi-pi! Pi-pi-pi-pi! Heh! Pi-pi-pi!
どーもー！イェーイ！
Hello! Yay!
これが私の桐生会のランウェイでございますわ！
This is my Kiryu-kai runway!
ここね、うん、桐生ここ。
Here, yes, Kiryu Coco.
最後にアイドル見せちゃうぞー！
I'm going to show you an idol at the last minute!
おおー！見せてくれるの？見せてくれるのかい？
Oh! You're going to show us? Are you really going to show us?
いいかい？
Is it okay?
みんな盛り上げてくれるかい？
Will everyone get hyped for me?
盛り上げるよー！任せてよー！
We'll get hyped! Leave it to us!
やってやんよー！
We're gonna do it!
お、腕組んどく、腕組んどく。
Oh, arm in arm, arm in arm.
じゃあ仕方ない、みんな、
Then it can't be helped, everyone,
最前列をやるよ！
let's do the front row!
オー！いいよー！
Oh! Okay!
おでこ組借らせてもらうぜ！
We'll lend you the Odeko-gumi!
みんなすまんな！
Sorry everyone!
おでこ組、最前列、限界オタク！
Odeko-gumi, front row, limit-breaking otaku!
それでは聴いてくれ、盛り上げてくれ！
Then please listen, get hyped!
私のオリジナルソング、Weather Hackers☆
My original song, Weather Hackers☆
負けそうなときは 勇気をあげるよ
When you're about to lose, I'll give you courage
今日も 眩しい笑顔で☆
Today too, with a dazzling smile☆
Weather Hackers☆
作詞・作曲：CielP
Lyrics/Composition: CielP
初めて出会ったときのことを覚えていますか？
Do you remember when we first met?
夢と希望あふれた目で
With eyes full of dreams and hope
空の向こう いつも眺めていたよね
You were always looking beyond the sky
きっと 特別なものなんていらないよ
Surely, you don't need anything special
前に進む 勇気があれば
As long as you have the courage to move forward
君が今踏み出した 力強い一歩で
With the powerful step you've just taken
どんな天気も 晴れてゆくよ
Any weather will clear up
（いくよー！1, 2, 3, Jump!!）
(Here we go! 1, 2, 3, Jump!!)
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
朝の光を 浴びた
Bathed in the morning light
みんなの ハートに
Into everyone's heart
元気を届けるんだ
I'll deliver energy
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
夢へと 走り出した
Started running towards dreams
みんなの 心に
Into everyone's heart
青空を届けるよ
I'll deliver the blue sky
負けそうなときは 勇気をあげるよ
When you're about to lose, I'll give you courage
今日も 眩しい笑顔で☆
Today too, with a dazzling smile☆
少しだけ頑張ったら 足を止めて休んでね
If you try just a little bit, stop and rest
ムダなことなんてないから
Because nothing is useless
振り返れば 全てが繋がってるよ
If you look back, everything is connected
輝いた想いを 遥かな風にのせて
Carrying the shining feelings on the distant wind
自由な空 羽広げたら
When you spread your wings in the free sky
「いつだって 前向いて歩いていけばいい」って
Saying "Just keep walking forward at any time"
君の 心も 晴れてゆくよ
Your heart will clear up too
（いくよー！ 1, 2, 3, Jump!!）
(Here we go! 1, 2, 3, Jump!!)
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
朝の光を 浴びた
Bathed in the morning light
みんなの ハートに
Into everyone's heart
元気を届けるんだ
I'll deliver energy
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
夢へと 走り出した
Started running towards dreams
みんなの 心に
Into everyone's heart
青空を届けるよ
I'll deliver the blue sky
疲れたときには 癒やしをあげるよ
When you're tired, I'll give you healing
飛ぼう 広げた翼で☆
Let's fly with our spread wings☆
ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
空に煌めく 雷光
Lightning shimmering in the sky
雷光！
Lightning!
響き渡った 咆哮
A resounding roar
咆哮！
Roar!
未来に輝く 栄光
Glory shining in the future
栄光！
Glory!
その夢を諦めるな
Don't give up on that dream
困難 理不尽も 上等
Hardships and absurdity, bring it on!
上等！
Bring it on!
まとめて跳ね返す 眼光
A glare that pushes them all back
眼光！
Glare!
Go your own way! 進め Right now!
Go your own way! Move forward right now!
Right now!
まだ見ぬ 空の向こうへ
Toward the sky yet unseen
いつまでも大好きだよ
I'll always love you
お疲れ様
You did your best
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
朝の光を浴びた
Bathed in the morning light
みんなのハートに
To everyone's hearts
元気を届けるんだ
I'm delivering energy
青空を届けるよ
I'll deliver the blue sky
泣きそうなときは
When you're about to cry
元気をあげるよ
I'll give you energy
行こう 素敵なスマイルで☆
Let's go with a wonderful smile☆
桐生ココ 卒業LIVE
Kiryu Coco Graduation LIVE